[
  {
    "id": 3001,
    "question": "maletas",
    "questionDetails": "Solamente esas dos maletas.",
    "answer": "suitcases, bags, luggage",
    "answerDetails": "Just those two suitcases."
  },
  {
    "id": 3002,
    "question": "discurso",
    "questionDetails": "La clase examinó la estructura de las oraciones en un discurso.",
    "answer": "discourse, address",
    "answerDetails": "The class examined sentence structures within a discourse."
  },
  {
    "id": 3003,
    "question": "supuestamente",
    "questionDetails": "Hubo rumores de una grieta entre él y sus colegas, supuestamente porque estaban celosos de su relación con la duquesa.",
    "answer": "supposedly, allegedly",
    "answerDetails": "There were rumours of a rift between him and his colleagues, supposedly because they were jealous of his relationship with the Duchess."
  },
  {
    "id": 3004,
    "question": "asiento",
    "questionDetails": "Por favor, tome asiento.",
    "answer": "seat",
    "answerDetails": "Please take a seat."
  },
  {
    "id": 3005,
    "question": "regalar",
    "answer": "gift"
  },
  {
    "id": 3006,
    "question": "etapa",
    "questionDetails": "La etapa final del viaje es hecha por el entrenador.",
    "answer": "stage, phase",
    "answerDetails": "The final stage of the journey is made by coach."
  },
  {
    "id": 3007,
    "question": "vehículo",
    "questionDetails": "¿Tienes vehículo o quieres que te lleve?",
    "answer": "transport, vehicle, conveyance",
    "answerDetails": "Do you have transport or do you want a ride?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3008,
    "question": "puente",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes cruzar el río a través del puente.",
    "answer": "bridge",
    "answerDetails": "You can cross the river using the bridge."
  },
  {
    "id": 3009,
    "question": "buscado",
    "questionDetails": "Su amistad fue muy buscado después.",
    "answer": "sought",
    "answerDetails": "Their acquaintance was exceedingly sought after."
  },
  {
    "id": 3010,
    "question": "pregúntale",
    "questionDetails": "Pregúntale cuánto quiere por su coche.",
    "answer": "ask him, ask her",
    "answerDetails": "Ask him how much he wants for his car."
  },
  {
    "id": 3011,
    "question": "entran",
    "questionDetails": "Entran dos robots, sale uno.",
    "answer": "enter",
    "answerDetails": "Two robots enter, one robot leaves."
  },
  {
    "id": 3012,
    "question": "molesto",
    "questionDetails": "Llamadas no solicitadas son molestos.",
    "answer": "annoying, upset, annoyed",
    "answerDetails": "Unsolicited calls are annoying."
  },
  {
    "id": 3013,
    "question": "estarán",
    "questionDetails": "Ustedes también lo estarán si no se ocupan de esto.",
    "answer": "are",
    "answerDetails": "So are you if you don’t deal with this situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 3014,
    "question": "parto",
    "questionDetails": "El parto fue complicado porque los pies del bebé salieron primero.",
    "answer": "delivery, childbirth, labor",
    "answerDetails": "The delivery was complicated because the baby’s feet came out first."
  },
  {
    "id": 3015,
    "question": "sienten",
    "questionDetails": "Los niños quieren disculparse. Sienten haberte mentido.",
    "answer": "they are sorry",
    "answerDetails": "The kids want to apologize. They are sorry they lied to you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3016,
    "question": "instante",
    "questionDetails": "El instante que entré a mi cuenta bancaria, supe que algo estaba mal.",
    "answer": "instant, moment",
    "answerDetails": "The instant I logged onto my bank account, I knew something was wrong."
  },
  {
    "id": 3017,
    "question": "habrás",
    "questionDetails": "Asumo que te les habrás acercado.",
    "answer": "‘ve",
    "answerDetails": "I assume you’ve approached them."
  },
  {
    "id": 3018,
    "question": "cuentan",
    "questionDetails": "Los niños del colegio de sordos no cuentan.",
    "answer": "count, feature, have",
    "answerDetails": "That kid at the deaf school don’t count!"
  },
  {
    "id": 3019,
    "question": "siglo",
    "questionDetails": "El siglo XIX.",
    "answer": "century",
    "answerDetails": "The 19th century."
  },
  {
    "id": 3020,
    "question": "apaga",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando dejes la carretera, apaga las luces.",
    "answer": "turn off, off",
    "answerDetails": "When you leave the highway, turn off all your lights."
  },
  {
    "id": 3021,
    "question": "escribe",
    "answer": "you are writing"
  },
  {
    "id": 3022,
    "question": "subí",
    "questionDetails": "Me subí al taxi al salir ustedes y hallé esto en …",
    "answer": "hopped, climbed, got",
    "answerDetails": "I hopped into the cab afteryou and found this on …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3023,
    "question": "periodista",
    "questionDetails": "El periodista que mataste me preguntó lo mismo.",
    "answer": "journalist",
    "answerDetails": "The journalist asked you fired too."
  },
  {
    "id": 3024,
    "question": "descanse",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero que usted descanse.",
    "answer": "rest",
    "answerDetails": "I want you to rest."
  },
  {
    "id": 3025,
    "question": "flor",
    "questionDetails": "Desperdició la flor de la juventud francesa en sus sueños de Imperio.",
    "answer": "flower, blossom",
    "answerDetails": "He wasted the flower of French youth on his dreams of empire."
  },
  {
    "id": 3026,
    "question": "encerrada",
    "questionDetails": "Estuvo encerrada en ese sitio durante mucho tiempo.",
    "answer": "cooped up, locked, enclosed",
    "answerDetails": "Cooped up in that place for so long."
  },
  {
    "id": 3027,
    "question": "dudo",
    "questionDetails": "No lo dudo amigo.",
    "answer": "doubt, doubtful",
    "answerDetails": "No doubt my friend."
  },
  {
    "id": 3028,
    "question": "competencia",
    "questionDetails": "La competencia de la corte ha sido aceptada para cubrir estos asuntos.",
    "answer": "competence",
    "answerDetails": "The Court’s competence has been accepted to cover these matters."
  },
  {
    "id": 3029,
    "question": "busque",
    "questionDetails": "Busque actividades que lo hagan feliz.",
    "answer": "try to find",
    "answerDetails": "Try to find activities that make you happy."
  },
  {
    "id": 3030,
    "question": "medicina",
    "questionDetails": "La medicina que uso para los dolores de cabeza está en el armario.",
    "answer": "medicine, medication",
    "answerDetails": "The medicine I use for headaches is in the cabinet."
  },
  {
    "id": 3031,
    "question": "estupidez",
    "questionDetails": "Salir con una mujer casada fue una verdadera estupidez. Me alegro de que dejaras de verla.",
    "answer": "stupidity, foolishness",
    "answerDetails": "Dating a married woman was a real stupidity. I’m glad you stopped seeing her."
  },
  {
    "id": 3032,
    "question": "separar",
    "questionDetails": "La segunda etapa del cohete no pudo separar.",
    "answer": "separate, detach",
    "answerDetails": "The second stage of the rocket failed to separate."
  },
  {
    "id": 3033,
    "question": "obligación",
    "questionDetails": "Tienes la obligación de ayudar a cuidar a tu hija.",
    "answer": "duty, obligation",
    "answerDetails": "You have a duty to help take care of your daughter."
  },
  {
    "id": 3034,
    "question": "whisky",
    "questionDetails": "Brian y sus amigos celebraron su jubilación con whisky escocés y puros.",
    "answer": "whiskey",
    "answerDetails": "Brian and his friends celebrated his retirement with Scotch whiskey and cigars."
  },
  {
    "id": 3035,
    "question": "pensarlo",
    "questionDetails": "Quizás deba pensarlo de nuevo.",
    "answer": "think",
    "answerDetails": "Maybe you should think again."
  },
  {
    "id": 3036,
    "question": "amar",
    "questionDetails": "Nos vamos a amar para siempre.",
    "answer": "love",
    "answerDetails": "Our love for ever and ever."
  },
  {
    "id": 3037,
    "question": "nuevamente",
    "questionDetails": "¿Nos leerías tu poesía nuevamente?",
    "answer": "again",
    "answerDetails": "Can you read your poem again for us?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3038,
    "question": "pagó",
    "questionDetails": "Ciertamente nunca le pagó ninguna a la cara.",
    "answer": "paid",
    "answerDetails": "He certainly never paid her any to her face."
  },
  {
    "id": 3039,
    "question": "autoridad",
    "questionDetails": "Las fuerzas armadas tienen la autoridad legal para arrestar a los narcotraficantes.",
    "answer": "authority",
    "answerDetails": "Military forces have the legal authority to arrest drug traffickers."
  },
  {
    "id": 3040,
    "question": "abandonar",
    "questionDetails": "Preferiría abandonar la nave ahora que renunciar en la vergüenza en 2 años.",
    "answer": "abandon, forsake",
    "answerDetails": "He would rather abandon ship now than resign in shame in two years."
  },
  {
    "id": 3041,
    "question": "dejarte",
    "questionDetails": "A dejarte una nota.",
    "answer": "leave",
    "answerDetails": "To leave a note."
  },
  {
    "id": 3042,
    "question": "romántico",
    "questionDetails": "Él es muy guapo, y tan romántico.",
    "answer": "romantic",
    "answerDetails": "He’s very handsome, and so romantic."
  },
  {
    "id": 3043,
    "question": "armado",
    "questionDetails": "El sospechoso está armado y es peligroso.",
    "answer": "armed",
    "answerDetails": "Suspect is armed and dangerous."
  },
  {
    "id": 3044,
    "question": "sirven",
    "questionDetails": "Ellos sirven para que nosotros no debamos hacerlo.",
    "answer": "serve",
    "answerDetails": "They serve so that we don’t have to."
  },
  {
    "id": 3045,
    "question": "disparo",
    "questionDetails": "El soldado resultó herido por un disparo en el brazo.",
    "answer": "shot",
    "answerDetails": "The soldier was injured by a shot to the arm."
  },
  {
    "id": 3046,
    "question": "urgencia",
    "questionDetails": "Varios delegados destacaron la urgencia de la situación.",
    "answer": "urgency",
    "answerDetails": "Several delegates emphasized the urgency of the situation."
  },
  {
    "id": 3047,
    "question": "suba",
    "questionDetails": "Antes de que suba.",
    "answer": "climb, raise, upload",
    "answerDetails": "Before you climb out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3048,
    "question": "infarto",
    "questionDetails": "Mi papá sufrió un infarto y lo tuvieron que operar a corazón abierto.",
    "answer": "heart attack, cardiac",
    "answerDetails": "My dad suffered a heart attack and had to have open-heart surgery."
  },
  {
    "id": 3049,
    "question": "sacarme",
    "questionDetails": "Debo sacarme estas ideas negras de la cabeza.",
    "answer": "get",
    "answerDetails": "I must get these dark thoughts out of my head."
  },
  {
    "id": 3050,
    "question": "enviar",
    "questionDetails": "Selecciona el archivo y luego pulsa el botón para enviar.",
    "answer": "submit, ship",
    "answerDetails": "Select the file and then hit the submit button."
  },
  {
    "id": 3051,
    "question": "comienzo",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes matricularte una semana antes del comienzo del curso.",
    "answer": "beginning, start, commencement",
    "answerDetails": "You can register one week before the beginning of the course."
  },
  {
    "id": 3052,
    "question": "prioridad",
    "questionDetails": "Le da prioridad a su familia sobre su trabajo.",
    "answer": "priority",
    "answerDetails": "She gives priority to her family over her job."
  },
  {
    "id": 3053,
    "question": "subió",
    "questionDetails": "Al final se subió al segundo piso.",
    "answer": "climbed, upped, ascended",
    "answerDetails": "In the end he climbed to the second floor."
  },
  {
    "id": 3054,
    "question": "tren",
    "questionDetails": "Una investigación está en el tren.",
    "answer": "train, rail, gear",
    "answerDetails": "An investigation is in train."
  },
  {
    "id": 3055,
    "question": "intentarlo",
    "questionDetails": "Hicieron bien en no intentarlo.",
    "answer": "try",
    "answerDetails": "You were smart not to try."
  },
  {
    "id": 3056,
    "question": "tomen",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando terminen, tomen sus lugares.",
    "answer": "take, grab",
    "answerDetails": "When you finish, take your place over there."
  },
  {
    "id": 3057,
    "question": "evidentemente",
    "questionDetails": "Un trabajo tan evidentemente cargado de importancia.",
    "answer": "evidently, obviously, clearly",
    "answerDetails": "A work so evidently Laden with significance."
  },
  {
    "id": 3058,
    "question": "buscarme",
    "answer": "me"
  },
  {
    "id": 3059,
    "question": "llevarme",
    "answer": "Take"
  },
  {
    "id": 3060,
    "question": "pierdo",
    "answer": "i miss"
  },
  {
    "id": 3061,
    "question": "suelto",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo que comprar talco suelto para fijar el maquillaje.",
    "answer": "loose",
    "answerDetails": "I need to buy some loose talc to fix my makeup."
  },
  {
    "id": 3062,
    "question": "especiales",
    "questionDetails": "Todos los que son especiales están bajo este techo.",
    "answer": "special, specialty",
    "answerDetails": "Everyone special to me is under this roof."
  },
  {
    "id": 3063,
    "question": "leyendo",
    "questionDetails": "Mamá me estaba leyendo.",
    "answer": "reading",
    "answerDetails": "Mother was reading to me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3064,
    "question": "conseguimos",
    "questionDetails": "Después de varios intentos, conseguimos la respuesta que queríamos de Ella.",
    "answer": "we got",
    "answerDetails": "After a few tries, we got the answer we wanted from her."
  },
  {
    "id": 3065,
    "question": "seres",
    "questionDetails": "Y casi sin contacto con seres orgánicos.",
    "answer": "beings, creatures",
    "answerDetails": "And he’s had almost no interaction with organic beings."
  },
  {
    "id": 3066,
    "question": "límite",
    "questionDetails": "Mary Ann intentó la paciencia de todos hasta el límite.",
    "answer": "limit, ceiling, cutoff",
    "answerDetails": "Mary Ann tried everyone’s patience to the limit."
  },
  {
    "id": 3067,
    "question": "metemos",
    "questionDetails": "Así es como nos metemos en líos cada tres años.",
    "answer": "get",
    "answerDetails": "This is how we get in trouble every three years."
  },
  {
    "id": 3068,
    "question": "caen",
    "questionDetails": "Y las ciudades se abandonan cuando las civilizaciones caen.",
    "answer": "fall, dropping, tumble",
    "answerDetails": "Cities are usually abandoned when civilisations fall."
  },
  {
    "id": 3069,
    "question": "sonar",
    "questionDetails": "Oí el reloj sonar y supe que era hora de levantarme.",
    "answer": "chime",
    "answerDetails": "I heard the clock chime and knew it was time to get up."
  },
  {
    "id": 3070,
    "question": "descubierto",
    "questionDetails": "El secreto descubierto impactó a todos.",
    "answer": "exposed",
    "answerDetails": "The exposed secret had an impact on everyone."
  },
  {
    "id": 3071,
    "question": "convierte",
    "questionDetails": "Lo que me convierte en.",
    "answer": "converts, turns, makes",
    "answerDetails": "What converts me in."
  },
  {
    "id": 3072,
    "question": "divino",
    "questionDetails": "El altar debe usarse exclusivamente para la celebración del culto divino.",
    "answer": "divine",
    "answerDetails": "The altar must be used exclusively for the celebration of the divine worship."
  },
  {
    "id": 3073,
    "question": "asesinato",
    "questionDetails": "El asesinato del hombre desarmado por la policía ocasionó protestas en la ciudad.",
    "answer": "killing",
    "answerDetails": "The killing of the unarmed man by police spurred protests in the city."
  },
  {
    "id": 3074,
    "question": "cositas",
    "questionDetails": "bala otras cositas acerca de que no estaba seguro de que …",
    "answer": "tidbits, things, goodies",
    "answerDetails": "bullet other tidbits about that i wasn’t sure you …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3075,
    "question": "flaco",
    "answer": "feeble"
  },
  {
    "id": 3076,
    "question": "militar",
    "questionDetails": "Academia militar.",
    "answer": "military",
    "answerDetails": "Military Academy."
  },
  {
    "id": 3077,
    "question": "dueña",
    "questionDetails": "La dueña anunció que solo quedaban 5 minutos para la hora de cierre.",
    "answer": "landlord",
    "answerDetails": "The landlord announced that there were only five minutes left till closing time."
  },
  {
    "id": 3078,
    "question": "terapia",
    "questionDetails": "Yolanda ha estado recibiendo terapia física 2 veces a la semana desde la cirugía.",
    "answer": "therapy",
    "answerDetails": "Yolanda has been receiving physical therapy twice a week since her surgery."
  },
  {
    "id": 3079,
    "question": "novedad",
    "questionDetails": "La novedad de ser una mujer casada se desgastó.",
    "answer": "novelty",
    "answerDetails": "The novelty of being a married woman wore off."
  },
  {
    "id": 3080,
    "question": "apúrate",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Apúrate!-No te preocupes. Mis amigos no se van a ir sin nosotros.",
    "answer": "hurry",
    "answerDetails": "Hurry!-Don’t worry. My friends won’t leave without us."
  },
  {
    "id": 3081,
    "question": "gastos",
    "questionDetails": "La compañía pagará los gastos de viaje incurridos por los candidatos.",
    "answer": "expenses",
    "answerDetails": "The company will cover any travel expenses incurred by interviewees."
  },
  {
    "id": 3082,
    "question": "uf",
    "questionDetails": "¿El arroz con mariscos cuesta $30? Uf, creo que mejor pido la hamburguesa.",
    "answer": "oof, whew",
    "answerDetails": "The Seafood Rice is $30? Oof, maybe I’ll just get the burger."
  },
  {
    "id": 3083,
    "question": "colgar",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo que colgar, me llaman.",
    "answer": "hang",
    "answerDetails": "I have to hang, they call me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3084,
    "question": "bendición",
    "questionDetails": "Su novela es tan grande que hasta diría que es una bendición para la humanidad.",
    "answer": "boon",
    "answerDetails": "Her novel is so great that I’d go so far as to call it a boon for humanity."
  },
  {
    "id": 3085,
    "question": "expediente",
    "questionDetails": "El expediente de seguridad en el aeropuerto es de primera clase.",
    "answer": "record, disciplinary proceedings",
    "answerDetails": "The safety record at the airport is first class."
  },
  {
    "id": 3086,
    "question": "segundito",
    "questionDetails": "… atrás acá en un segundito.",
    "answer": "second",
    "answerDetails": "… back here in just a second."
  },
  {
    "id": 3087,
    "question": "despedir",
    "questionDetails": "Sería fácil despedirlo como todo el músculo y ningún cerebro.",
    "answer": "dismiss",
    "answerDetails": "It would be easy to dismiss him as all brawn and no brain."
  },
  {
    "id": 3088,
    "question": "inmediato",
    "questionDetails": "En un futuro inmediato.",
    "answer": "immediate",
    "answerDetails": "In the immediate future."
  },
  {
    "id": 3089,
    "question": "brindis",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Quiero proponer un brindis por los novios!.",
    "answer": "toast",
    "answerDetails": "I’d like to propose a toast to the bride and groom!."
  },
  {
    "id": 3090,
    "question": "faltar",
    "answer": "missing"
  },
  {
    "id": 3091,
    "question": "verle",
    "questionDetails": "Tanto tiempo sin verle.",
    "answer": "see",
    "answerDetails": "Long time no see."
  },
  {
    "id": 3092,
    "question": "abran",
    "questionDetails": "Pónganse las estrellas en el pecho y abran el sobre.",
    "answer": "open",
    "answerDetails": "Place the stars on your chest and open the envelope."
  },
  {
    "id": 3093,
    "question": "teléfonos",
    "questionDetails": "Tenían teléfonos de campo conectados por toda el área.",
    "answer": "phones, telephones, handsets",
    "answerDetails": "They had field phones strung all over the area."
  },
  {
    "id": 3094,
    "question": "metan",
    "questionDetails": "Diles que se las metan por ahí.",
    "answer": "shove, get",
    "answerDetails": "You tell them they can shove it."
  },
  {
    "id": 3095,
    "question": "suceder",
    "questionDetails": "Suceder voy a volver sólo por un tiempo.",
    "answer": "happen",
    "answerDetails": "Happen I’ll go back just for a while."
  },
  {
    "id": 3096,
    "question": "espectáculo",
    "questionDetails": "Hay un espectáculo nuevo maravilloso en el teatro.",
    "answer": "show, exhibition, spectacle",
    "answerDetails": "There is a wonderful new show at the theater."
  },
  {
    "id": 3097,
    "question": "quitarle",
    "questionDetails": "No quiero quitarle la vida.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "I will not take her life."
  },
  {
    "id": 3098,
    "question": "plena",
    "questionDetails": "La plena responsabilidad se asume.",
    "answer": "full, fully, broad",
    "answerDetails": "Full responsibility will be assumed."
  },
  {
    "id": 3099,
    "question": "profesionales",
    "questionDetails": "Para los temas profesionales, recurre a mí.",
    "answer": "professional, profesionals, practitioners",
    "answerDetails": "For your professional needs, talk to me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3100,
    "question": "tensión",
    "questionDetails": "La tensión básica entre la libertad y el control.",
    "answer": "tension",
    "answerDetails": "The basic tension between freedom and control."
  },
  {
    "id": 3101,
    "question": "gastar",
    "questionDetails": "Y no habrá muchas ocasiones de gastar.",
    "answer": "spend",
    "answerDetails": "And it will not have many occasions to spend."
  },
  {
    "id": 3102,
    "question": "quitarme",
    "questionDetails": "Y quitarme mis cosas y luego.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "And take my things from me and then."
  },
  {
    "id": 3103,
    "question": "firmado",
    "questionDetails": "Este es un formulario de consentimiento firmado.",
    "answer": "signed",
    "answerDetails": "This is a signed consent form."
  },
  {
    "id": 3104,
    "question": "perdemos",
    "questionDetails": "Ganamos o perdemos juntos.",
    "answer": "lose",
    "answerDetails": "We gain or lose together."
  },
  {
    "id": 3105,
    "question": "encontraba",
    "questionDetails": "Encontraba toda clase de razones y excusas.",
    "answer": "found",
    "answerDetails": "I found all kinds of reasons and excuses."
  },
  {
    "id": 3106,
    "question": "serlo",
    "questionDetails": "Muy severa, tiene que serlo.",
    "answer": "be",
    "answerDetails": "It has to be."
  },
  {
    "id": 3107,
    "question": "situaciones",
    "questionDetails": "Trabaja bien en situaciones de grupo.",
    "answer": "situations, scenarios",
    "answerDetails": "Works well in group situations."
  },
  {
    "id": 3108,
    "question": "leído",
    "questionDetails": "He leído que va más rápido si caminas.",
    "answer": "read",
    "answerDetails": "I read it goes faster if you walk around."
  },
  {
    "id": 3109,
    "question": "continúa",
    "questionDetails": "Y el ciclo continúa.",
    "answer": "continues, remains",
    "answerDetails": "And on the cycle continues."
  },
  {
    "id": 3110,
    "question": "preguntan",
    "questionDetails": "Los campesinos preguntan por la oración de la lluvia.",
    "answer": "ask, wonder",
    "answerDetails": "Peasants ask about the rain prayer."
  },
  {
    "id": 3111,
    "question": "güey",
    "questionDetails": "Ese es el problema del cerebro, güey.",
    "answer": "dude",
    "answerDetails": "That is the problem with the brain, dude."
  },
  {
    "id": 3112,
    "question": "mirá",
    "questionDetails": "Y mirá lo que pasó.",
    "answer": "look",
    "answerDetails": "And look what happened."
  },
  {
    "id": 3113,
    "question": "jorge",
    "answer": "Jorge"
  },
  {
    "id": 3114,
    "question": "bye",
    "questionDetails": "… en el próximo video, bye!",
    "answer": "bye",
    "answerDetails": "… in the next video, bye!"
  },
  {
    "id": 3115,
    "question": "julio",
    "answer": "July"
  },
  {
    "id": 3116,
    "question": "entendió",
    "questionDetails": "Le mostré la canción a Federico, y entendió la letra porque habla español.",
    "answer": "he understood, he saw, she knew",
    "answerDetails": "I played the song for Federico, and he understood the lyrics because he speaks Spanish."
  },
  {
    "id": 3117,
    "question": "entienda",
    "questionDetails": "Espero que lo entienda.",
    "answer": "understand",
    "answerDetails": "I think you can understand that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3118,
    "question": "imagina",
    "questionDetails": "Imagina el conocimiento que está esperando.",
    "answer": "imagine, pretend, suppose",
    "answerDetails": "Imagine the knowledge that waits."
  },
  {
    "id": 3119,
    "question": "estáis",
    "questionDetails": "Así que estáis viviendo aquí.",
    "answer": "are, ye",
    "answerDetails": "So you are living here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3120,
    "question": "colaborar",
    "questionDetails": "Durante la última guerra colaboraron con los nazis.",
    "answer": "collaborate",
    "answerDetails": "During the last war they collaborated with the Nazis."
  },
  {
    "id": 3121,
    "question": "kilos",
    "questionDetails": "Ciento trece kilos con cincuenta gramos.",
    "answer": "kilos, pounds, extra pounds",
    "answerDetails": "A hundred and thirteen kilos and fifty grams."
  },
  {
    "id": 3122,
    "question": "decente",
    "questionDetails": "Un vestido de cuello alto decente.",
    "answer": "decent",
    "answerDetails": "A decent high-necked dress."
  },
  {
    "id": 3123,
    "question": "logró",
    "questionDetails": "El ideal de la medicina preventiva se logró.",
    "answer": "attained, managed, accomplished",
    "answerDetails": "The ideal of preventive medicine was attained."
  },
  {
    "id": 3124,
    "question": "territorio",
    "questionDetails": "Viene con el territorio.",
    "answer": "territory",
    "answerDetails": "Comes with the territory."
  },
  {
    "id": 3125,
    "question": "cometer",
    "questionDetails": "O cuando se puede cometer el acto.",
    "answer": "commit",
    "answerDetails": "Or when they may commit the act."
  },
  {
    "id": 3126,
    "question": "contratar",
    "questionDetails": "Los Reyes obtuvieron dispensaciones para permitirles contratar partidos políticamente ventajosos.",
    "answer": "contract, employ",
    "answerDetails": "Kings obtained dispensations to enable them to contract politically advantageous matches."
  },
  {
    "id": 3127,
    "question": "amén",
    "questionDetails": "En el nombre de nuestro Sr. Jesucristo. Amén.",
    "answer": "amen",
    "answerDetails": "In the name of our Lord, Jesus Christ. Amen."
  },
  {
    "id": 3128,
    "question": "injusto",
    "questionDetails": "En momentos como estos el sistema legal parece inhumano e injusto.",
    "answer": "unfair",
    "answerDetails": "At times like these the legal system appears inhuman and unfair."
  },
  {
    "id": 3129,
    "question": "ayudarlo",
    "questionDetails": "Mi hijo tiene problemas, pero no sé cómo ayudarlo.",
    "answer": "help him",
    "answerDetails": "My son has problems, but I don’t know how to help him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3130,
    "question": "recomiendo",
    "answer": "Recommend"
  },
  {
    "id": 3131,
    "question": "lección",
    "questionDetails": "Entonces aprendiste una valiosa lección.",
    "answer": "lesson",
    "answerDetails": "So then you’ve learned a valuable moral lesson."
  },
  {
    "id": 3132,
    "question": "pensabas",
    "questionDetails": "Antes en el campamento de verano, nunca pensabas.",
    "answer": "thought",
    "answerDetails": "Back in summer camp, you never thought."
  },
  {
    "id": 3133,
    "question": "pedirme",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes pedirme cualquier cosa que necesites.",
    "answer": "ask me",
    "answerDetails": "You can ask me for anything you need."
  },
  {
    "id": 3134,
    "question": "salgamos",
    "questionDetails": "Todo volverá a comenzar una vez que salgamos de ésta.",
    "answer": "out",
    "answerDetails": "Everything starts over once we make it out of this."
  },
  {
    "id": 3135,
    "question": "ocultar",
    "questionDetails": "Estaban en gran esfuerzo para ocultar esa información del público.",
    "answer": "conceal",
    "answerDetails": "They were at great pains to conceal that information from the public."
  },
  {
    "id": 3136,
    "question": "madrugada",
    "questionDetails": "Estudiamos hasta las 5 de la madrugada.",
    "answer": "morning, dawn",
    "answerDetails": "We were studying till five in the morning."
  },
  {
    "id": 3137,
    "question": "llegara",
    "questionDetails": "Al poco de que él llegara.",
    "answer": "arrived, came",
    "answerDetails": "Soon after he arrived."
  },
  {
    "id": 3138,
    "question": "fuente",
    "questionDetails": "Este problema es la fuente de todos mis frustraciones.",
    "answer": "source, supply, font",
    "answerDetails": "This problem is the source of all my frustrations."
  },
  {
    "id": 3139,
    "question": "humilde",
    "questionDetails": "En mi humilde opinión.",
    "answer": "humble, lowly",
    "answerDetails": "In my humble opinion."
  },
  {
    "id": 3140,
    "question": "dándole",
    "questionDetails": "Dándole a las cosas un aire de final.",
    "answer": "giving",
    "answerDetails": "Just giving things a finale vibe."
  },
  {
    "id": 3141,
    "question": "grupos",
    "questionDetails": "Me siento cómodo hablando en grupos pequeños.",
    "answer": "groups, bands, sets",
    "answerDetails": "I am perfectly comfortable speaking to small groups."
  },
  {
    "id": 3142,
    "question": "escuchen",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero que ustedes dos me escuchen.",
    "answer": "listen, heed",
    "answerDetails": "I want you two to listen to me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3143,
    "question": "mantiene",
    "questionDetails": "Mantiene alejada la oscuridad.",
    "answer": "keeps, maintains, holds",
    "answerDetails": "Keeps the dark away."
  },
  {
    "id": 3144,
    "question": "gesto",
    "questionDetails": "Maggie fue tocado por el gesto amable.",
    "answer": "gesture",
    "answerDetails": "Maggie was touched by the kind gesture."
  },
  {
    "id": 3145,
    "question": "inicio",
    "questionDetails": "El pasado jueves marcó el inicio oficial de la campaña electoral.",
    "answer": "start, beginning, onset",
    "answerDetails": "Last Thursday marked the official start of the electoral campaign."
  },
  {
    "id": 3146,
    "question": "absoluto",
    "questionDetails": "Los expertos clasificaron la campaña como un fracaso absoluto.",
    "answer": "unqualified",
    "answerDetails": "The pundits declared the campaign an unqualified disaster."
  },
  {
    "id": 3147,
    "question": "falla",
    "questionDetails": "Los sistemas de calefacción no suelen descomponerse por una falla grave sino por falta de Mantenimiento.",
    "answer": "fault, defect, flaw",
    "answerDetails": "Heating systems generally break down because of a lack of maintenance and not because of a major fault."
  },
  {
    "id": 3148,
    "question": "atento",
    "questionDetails": "Él era atento y reflexivo.",
    "answer": "thoughtful",
    "answerDetails": "He was attentive and thoughtful."
  },
  {
    "id": 3149,
    "question": "trataba",
    "questionDetails": "Creí que se trataba de otro juego.",
    "answer": "was, tried, treated",
    "answerDetails": "I thought it was for a stud game."
  },
  {
    "id": 3150,
    "question": "venden",
    "questionDetails": "Algunos asesores venden productos financieros.",
    "answer": "sell",
    "answerDetails": "Some planners also sell financial products."
  },
  {
    "id": 3151,
    "question": "experto",
    "questionDetails": "La opinión de un experto.",
    "answer": "expert, skilled",
    "answerDetails": "An expert opinion."
  },
  {
    "id": 3152,
    "question": "motor",
    "questionDetails": "Lo he intentado varias veces, pero el motor no arranca.",
    "answer": "engine",
    "answerDetails": "I’ve tried several times, but the engine won’t start."
  },
  {
    "id": 3153,
    "question": "humo",
    "questionDetails": "Más de un sueño está a punto de subir en el humo.",
    "answer": "smoke",
    "answerDetails": "More than one dream is about to go up in smoke."
  },
  {
    "id": 3154,
    "question": "hacíamos",
    "answer": "we did"
  },
  {
    "id": 3155,
    "question": "típico",
    "questionDetails": "El hoyo es típico del infierno.",
    "answer": "typical",
    "answerDetails": "The pit is typical of hell."
  },
  {
    "id": 3156,
    "question": "antiguo",
    "questionDetails": "Un antiguo amor un ex amor.",
    "answer": "old",
    "answerDetails": "An old flame."
  },
  {
    "id": 3157,
    "question": "patio",
    "answer": "patio"
  },
  {
    "id": 3158,
    "question": "inteligencia",
    "questionDetails": "El jefe de la inteligencia militar.",
    "answer": "intelligence",
    "answerDetails": "The chief of military intelligence."
  },
  {
    "id": 3159,
    "question": "rueda",
    "questionDetails": "El lanzamiento final de la rueda de la vida.",
    "answer": "wheel",
    "answerDetails": "The final release from the Wheel of life."
  },
  {
    "id": 3160,
    "question": "felicitaciones",
    "questionDetails": "Felicitaciones por el concurso.",
    "answer": "congratulations",
    "answerDetails": "Congratulations on winning the contest."
  },
  {
    "id": 3161,
    "question": "ayudarla",
    "questionDetails": "Quería ayudarla, pero simplemente no tenía tiempo.",
    "answer": "help her",
    "answerDetails": "I wanted to help her, but I just didn’t have time."
  },
  {
    "id": 3162,
    "question": "enteró",
    "questionDetails": "Aquí se enteró de quién era.",
    "answer": "learned",
    "answerDetails": "This is where he learned who he was."
  },
  {
    "id": 3163,
    "question": "soporto",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo lo soporto si él está allí.",
    "answer": "stand",
    "answerDetails": "I can only stand it when he’s there."
  },
  {
    "id": 3164,
    "question": "aguas",
    "questionDetails": "El barco entró en aguas extranjeras.",
    "answer": "waters",
    "answerDetails": "The ship entered foreign waters."
  },
  {
    "id": 3165,
    "question": "dato",
    "questionDetails": "Aprendí un dato interesante leyendo un artículo sobre ese actor. Resulta que habla 5 idiomas.",
    "answer": "tidbit",
    "answerDetails": "I learned an interesting tidbit reading an article about that actor. It turns out he speaks five languages."
  },
  {
    "id": 3166,
    "question": "cago",
    "questionDetails": "Me cago en eso.",
    "answer": "shit",
    "answerDetails": "I shit on that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3167,
    "question": "dejarla",
    "questionDetails": "Tuve que dejarla, para ganar dinero.",
    "answer": "leave",
    "answerDetails": "I had to leave it, to make money."
  },
  {
    "id": 3168,
    "question": "traición",
    "questionDetails": "Ese panfleto es alta traición.",
    "answer": "treason",
    "answerDetails": "That pamphlet is high treason."
  },
  {
    "id": 3169,
    "question": "sacarle",
    "questionDetails": "Para sacarle el veneno.",
    "answer": "get",
    "answerDetails": "To get the poison out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3170,
    "question": "navidad",
    "questionDetails": "Mis padres estaban encantados de que los podía visitar para la Navidad.",
    "answer": "christmas",
    "answerDetails": "My parents were delighted that I was able to visit for Christmas."
  },
  {
    "id": 3171,
    "question": "echarle",
    "questionDetails": "Quizá deberías echarle un vistazo.",
    "answer": "take, blame",
    "answerDetails": "Maybe you should take a look."
  },
  {
    "id": 3172,
    "question": "consejos",
    "questionDetails": "No hay consejos rápidos.",
    "answer": "tips, advice, councils",
    "answerDetails": "There are no quick tips."
  },
  {
    "id": 3173,
    "question": "preocuparte",
    "questionDetails": "Tan sólo no quería preocuparte.",
    "answer": "worry, fretting",
    "answerDetails": "I just didn’t want to worry you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3174,
    "question": "modos",
    "questionDetails": "Se llaman modos de cavidad.",
    "answer": "modes, ways",
    "answerDetails": "They are called cavity modes."
  },
  {
    "id": 3175,
    "question": "cuerpos",
    "questionDetails": "Hemos encontrado los cuerpos.",
    "answer": "bodies, corps",
    "answerDetails": "We found it by the bodies."
  },
  {
    "id": 3176,
    "question": "logrado",
    "answer": "authentic"
  },
  {
    "id": 3177,
    "question": "preocuparse",
    "questionDetails": "Comenzó a preocuparse por el nudo en la cuerda.",
    "answer": "worry",
    "answerDetails": "He began to worry at the knot in the cord."
  },
  {
    "id": 3178,
    "question": "sorpresas",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo que guardar algunas sorpresas.",
    "answer": "surprises",
    "answerDetails": "I gotta keep some surprises."
  },
  {
    "id": 3179,
    "question": "heridas",
    "questionDetails": "Aunque estas heridas no son nada.",
    "answer": "wounds, injuries, gunshot wounds",
    "answerDetails": "Yet these wounds are nothing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3180,
    "question": "echaron",
    "questionDetails": "Por eso la echaron de su antigua escuela.",
    "answer": "got kicked out",
    "answerDetails": "That’s why she got kicked out of her old school."
  },
  {
    "id": 3181,
    "question": "planeado",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie podía haberlo planeado.",
    "answer": "planned",
    "answerDetails": "Nobody could have planned this."
  },
  {
    "id": 3182,
    "question": "participar",
    "questionDetails": "La directora ejecutiva fue invitada pero decidió no participar.",
    "answer": "take part",
    "answerDetails": "The CEO was invited but decided not to take part."
  },
  {
    "id": 3183,
    "question": "título",
    "questionDetails": "El título del cuento es “Lobo Caprichoso”.",
    "answer": "title, heading",
    "answerDetails": "The title of the story is “Wayward Wolf.”."
  },
  {
    "id": 3184,
    "question": "baila",
    "answer": "Dance"
  },
  {
    "id": 3185,
    "question": "billetes",
    "answer": "paper money"
  },
  {
    "id": 3186,
    "question": "llamarme",
    "answer": "call me"
  },
  {
    "id": 3187,
    "question": "disfrutando",
    "questionDetails": "Demuestra que estás disfrutando la comida.",
    "answer": "enjoying, basking",
    "answerDetails": "It shows that you are enjoying a meal."
  },
  {
    "id": 3188,
    "question": "sonido",
    "questionDetails": "¿Qué es ese sonido?",
    "answer": "sound",
    "answerDetails": "What’s that sound?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3189,
    "question": "hacerla",
    "questionDetails": "Dijeron que podían hacerla de nuevo.",
    "answer": "make",
    "answerDetails": "They said they could make a new one."
  },
  {
    "id": 3190,
    "question": "únicos",
    "questionDetails": "Yo nunca he afirmado que mis poderes sean únicos.",
    "answer": "unique, only, sole",
    "answerDetails": "I never claimed that my powers were unique."
  },
  {
    "id": 3191,
    "question": "organizado",
    "questionDetails": "Bien organizado, lo hemos pasado bien.",
    "answer": "organized",
    "answerDetails": "Well organized, we had fun."
  },
  {
    "id": 3192,
    "question": "enterarse",
    "answer": "find out"
  },
  {
    "id": 3193,
    "question": "árbol",
    "questionDetails": "Árbol de levas.",
    "answer": "shaft, tree",
    "answerDetails": "Camshaft."
  },
  {
    "id": 3194,
    "question": "esconde",
    "questionDetails": "Cada hombre esconde una pena secreta.",
    "answer": "hides, conceals, lurking",
    "answerDetails": "Each man hides a secret pain."
  },
  {
    "id": 3195,
    "question": "regla",
    "questionDetails": "Tienes que seguir las reglas del juego.",
    "answer": "rule",
    "answerDetails": "You must follow the rules of the game."
  },
  {
    "id": 3196,
    "question": "subo",
    "questionDetails": "Yo subo siempre por las escaleras.",
    "answer": "climb, upload, raise",
    "answerDetails": "I climb the stairs every morning."
  },
  {
    "id": 3197,
    "question": "demos",
    "questionDetails": "Demos no puede hablar, el testigo tampoco.",
    "answer": "demos",
    "answerDetails": "Demos cannot speak, the witness cannot speak."
  },
  {
    "id": 3198,
    "question": "explica",
    "answer": "Explains"
  },
  {
    "id": 3199,
    "question": "puesta",
    "questionDetails": "… del período de armisticio y la puesta de los fundamentos para …",
    "answer": "laying",
    "answerDetails": "… of the armistice and the laying of the foundation for …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3200,
    "question": "raras",
    "questionDetails": "Ambos luchan con complejas cuerdas y raras melodías.",
    "answer": "rare, weird, strange",
    "answerDetails": "Both wrestle with complex chords and rare melodies."
  },
  {
    "id": 3201,
    "question": "partida",
    "questionDetails": "Las trompetas señalaban la partida del rey.",
    "answer": "departure, heading, item",
    "answerDetails": "The trumpets signaled the departure of the king."
  },
  {
    "id": 3202,
    "question": "lento",
    "questionDetails": "Ella era más bien un lector lento.",
    "answer": "slow",
    "answerDetails": "She was rather a slow reader."
  },
  {
    "id": 3203,
    "question": "rompe",
    "questionDetails": "Siempre se rompe la suya.",
    "answer": "breaks, smashes, shattering",
    "answerDetails": "He always breaks his own."
  },
  {
    "id": 3204,
    "question": "conocida",
    "questionDetails": "Joanna es una conocida mía.",
    "answer": "acquaintance",
    "answerDetails": "Joanna is an acquaintance of mine."
  },
  {
    "id": 3205,
    "question": "lee",
    "questionDetails": "Lee la letra pequeña de tu contrato.",
    "answer": "read",
    "answerDetails": "Read the fine print in your contract."
  },
  {
    "id": 3206,
    "question": "infancia",
    "questionDetails": "Ese olor me trae recuerdos de mi infancia.",
    "answer": "childhood",
    "answerDetails": "That smell brings me memories of my childhood."
  },
  {
    "id": 3207,
    "question": "sabés",
    "questionDetails": "Sabés que puedes tener intimidad de muchas maneras?",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "You know you can be intimate in many ways?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3208,
    "question": "asistente",
    "questionDetails": "Todos los asistentes dijeron que la junta salió bien.",
    "answer": "attendant, aide",
    "answerDetails": "All the attendants said the meeting went off well."
  },
  {
    "id": 3209,
    "question": "penal",
    "questionDetails": "El reo tuvo que cumplir 4 años en el penal de Santa María.",
    "answer": "prison",
    "answerDetails": "The criminal had to serve four years in Santa Maria prison."
  },
  {
    "id": 3210,
    "question": "porquería",
    "questionDetails": "Para mí, esta sopa no es nada más que una porquería aderezada.",
    "answer": "muck, crud, goo",
    "answerDetails": "As far as I’m concerned, this soup is just flavoured muck."
  },
  {
    "id": 3211,
    "question": "permítame",
    "answer": "allow me"
  },
  {
    "id": 3212,
    "question": "encantó",
    "questionDetails": "Por cierto, a todos nos encantó su espectáculo.",
    "answer": "loved, absolutely loved, delighted",
    "answerDetails": "By the way, we all loved your show."
  },
  {
    "id": 3213,
    "question": "víctimas",
    "questionDetails": "Esta sala es para las víctimas de caídas aéreas.",
    "answer": "victims, casualties, vics",
    "answerDetails": "This ward is reserved for air crash victims."
  },
  {
    "id": 3214,
    "question": "hablarle",
    "questionDetails": "Todo lo que haces andar y hablarle a la gente.",
    "answer": "talk",
    "answerDetails": "All you do is walk around and talk to people."
  },
  {
    "id": 3215,
    "question": "periodistas",
    "questionDetails": "Los periodistas rodearon a la actriz haciéndole preguntas.",
    "answer": "press",
    "answerDetails": "The press surrounded the actress asking her questions."
  },
  {
    "id": 3216,
    "question": "enfrentar",
    "questionDetails": "Debemos trabajar como comunidad para enfrentar el problema del acoso Escolar.",
    "answer": "tackle, pit",
    "answerDetails": "We should work as a community to tackle the problem of bullying."
  },
  {
    "id": 3217,
    "question": "hermanas",
    "questionDetails": "Extraño a mis hermanos y hermanas.",
    "answer": "sisters",
    "answerDetails": "I miss my brothers and sisters."
  },
  {
    "id": 3218,
    "question": "envidia",
    "questionDetails": "Francia tiene una industria cinematográfica que es la envidia de Europa.",
    "answer": "envy",
    "answerDetails": "France has a film industry that is the envy of Europe."
  },
  {
    "id": 3219,
    "question": "logramos",
    "questionDetails": "Lo logramos, a pesar de todos los obstáculos.",
    "answer": "we made it",
    "answerDetails": "We made it, in spite of all the obstacles."
  },
  {
    "id": 3220,
    "question": "gustas",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que le gustas.",
    "answer": "like",
    "answerDetails": "I think you like her."
  },
  {
    "id": 3221,
    "question": "casarse",
    "questionDetails": "Fue a casarse con la hija del rey.",
    "answer": "wed",
    "answerDetails": "He was to wed the King’s daughter."
  },
  {
    "id": 3222,
    "question": "asesinos",
    "questionDetails": "La gente necesita alivio o se vuelven asesinos.",
    "answer": "murderers, killers, assassins",
    "answerDetails": "People need relief or they become murderers."
  },
  {
    "id": 3223,
    "question": "recuerde",
    "questionDetails": "Recuerde, toda esa sal y arena.",
    "answer": "remember, remind, recall",
    "answerDetails": "But remember, all that salt and grime."
  },
  {
    "id": 3224,
    "question": "avisa",
    "questionDetails": "Avisa a todos, la clave a sido robada.",
    "answer": "warns, alerts",
    "answerDetails": "Warns of all, the key to been stolen."
  },
  {
    "id": 3225,
    "question": "tumba",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando los arqueólogos entraron a la tumba, la momia salió de golpe del sarcófago.",
    "answer": "tomb, grave",
    "answerDetails": "When the archaeologists entered the tomb, the mummy burst out of the sarcophagus."
  },
  {
    "id": 3226,
    "question": "denunciar",
    "questionDetails": "Vamos a denunciar todo.",
    "answer": "denounce",
    "answerDetails": "We are going to denounce everything."
  },
  {
    "id": 3227,
    "question": "angustia",
    "questionDetails": "Una causa importante de angustia entre los habitantes de una ciudad es el alza del precio de los alquileres.",
    "answer": "distress",
    "answerDetails": "A main cause of distress for city dwellers is rising rents."
  },
  {
    "id": 3228,
    "question": "sano",
    "questionDetails": "Un desprecio sano por la autoridad.",
    "answer": "healthy, sound",
    "answerDetails": "A healthy contempt for authority."
  },
  {
    "id": 3229,
    "question": "caiga",
    "questionDetails": "Queremos que caiga en sus manos.",
    "answer": "fall, drop",
    "answerDetails": "We want it to fall into their hands."
  },
  {
    "id": 3230,
    "question": "saludos",
    "questionDetails": "El dorso de la postal decía: “Saludos desde Barcelona”.",
    "answer": "greetings, regards",
    "answerDetails": "The back of the postcard said: “Greetings from Barcelona.”."
  },
  {
    "id": 3231,
    "question": "cajas",
    "questionDetails": "Nuestro futuro está en esas cajas.",
    "answer": "boxes, crates, cases",
    "answerDetails": "Our future is in those boxes."
  },
  {
    "id": 3232,
    "question": "comisión",
    "questionDetails": "Su primera comisión como escritora independiente fue escribir una obra para una compañía de teatro.",
    "answer": "commission",
    "answerDetails": "For her first commission as a freelance writer, she wrote a play for a theater company."
  },
  {
    "id": 3233,
    "question": "claras",
    "questionDetails": "Varios detalles de la historia nunca llegan a ser claras.",
    "answer": "clear",
    "answerDetails": "Several details of the story never become clear."
  },
  {
    "id": 3234,
    "question": "haberle",
    "questionDetails": "Deberías haberle devuelto al hombre su dinero.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "You should have given that man his money back."
  },
  {
    "id": 3235,
    "question": "cómoda",
    "questionDetails": "Puse tu suéter azul en el cajón de abajo de la cómoda.",
    "answer": "dresser, commode",
    "answerDetails": "I put your blue sweater in the bottom drawer of the dresser."
  },
  {
    "id": 3236,
    "question": "muchísima",
    "questionDetails": "A vuestro favor tenéis que nos ve muchísima gente.",
    "answer": "many",
    "answerDetails": "The good thing is that many people see us."
  },
  {
    "id": 3237,
    "question": "revista",
    "questionDetails": "Solía leer revistas para adolescentes cuando tenía 15 años.",
    "answer": "magazine, journal, revue",
    "answerDetails": "I used to read magazines for teenagers when I was 15."
  },
  {
    "id": 3238,
    "question": "lleves",
    "questionDetails": "Necesito que me lleves a casa.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "I need you to take me home."
  },
  {
    "id": 3239,
    "question": "insoportable",
    "questionDetails": "El calor se estaba volviendo insoportable.",
    "answer": "unbearable, excruciating, insupportable",
    "answerDetails": "The heat was getting unbearable."
  },
  {
    "id": 3240,
    "question": "cuchillo",
    "questionDetails": "Aquí al costado, un cuchillo.",
    "answer": "knife",
    "answerDetails": "In the side here, flat throwing knife."
  },
  {
    "id": 3241,
    "question": "mapa",
    "questionDetails": "Creció en una ciudad de Hick, justo al lado del mapa.",
    "answer": "map",
    "answerDetails": "She grew up in a hick town, right off the map."
  },
  {
    "id": 3242,
    "question": "ideal",
    "questionDetails": "Si nos puedes recoger a las 8 am, eso sería ideal.",
    "answer": "perfect",
    "answerDetails": "If you could pick us up at 8 A.M., that would be perfect."
  },
  {
    "id": 3243,
    "question": "conociste",
    "questionDetails": "La conociste de niños, ¿no?",
    "answer": "you knew",
    "answerDetails": "You knew her when you were kids, didn’t you?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3244,
    "question": "sensible",
    "questionDetails": "El nuevo método de detección de proteínas era más sensible que los anteriores.",
    "answer": "sensitive, responsive, noticeable",
    "answerDetails": "The new method of protein detection was more sensitive than earlier ones."
  },
  {
    "id": 3245,
    "question": "busqué",
    "questionDetails": "Fui tras el incendio y busqué.",
    "answer": "searched, looked",
    "answerDetails": "I went there right after the fire and searched."
  },
  {
    "id": 3246,
    "question": "guardado",
    "questionDetails": "El archivo ha sido guardado.",
    "answer": "saved, kept, guarded",
    "answerDetails": "The file is saved."
  },
  {
    "id": 3247,
    "question": "pasear",
    "questionDetails": "A la nueva mamá le encanta pasear por el barrio con su bebé.",
    "answer": "walking",
    "answerDetails": "The new mom loves walking around the neighborhood with her baby."
  },
  {
    "id": 3248,
    "question": "cumplido",
    "questionDetails": "Hacer un cumplido a alguien.",
    "answer": "compliment",
    "answerDetails": "To pay somebody a compliment."
  },
  {
    "id": 3249,
    "question": "iría",
    "answer": "Go"
  },
  {
    "id": 3250,
    "question": "seguía",
    "questionDetails": "En la escuela, seguía las instrucciones de la maestra cada día.",
    "answer": "she followed",
    "answerDetails": "In school, she followed the teacher’s directions every day."
  },
  {
    "id": 3251,
    "question": "controlado",
    "answer": "controlled"
  },
  {
    "id": 3252,
    "question": "pesa",
    "questionDetails": "¿Cuál la pesa más pesada que has levantado?",
    "answer": "dumbbell",
    "answerDetails": "What’s the heaviest dumbbell you’ve ever lifted?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3253,
    "question": "aprendiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Quizás estamos aprendiendo el arte de abarcar.",
    "answer": "learning, Iearning",
    "answerDetails": "Maybe we are learning the art of embracing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3254,
    "question": "disfruten",
    "answer": "Enjoy"
  },
  {
    "id": 3255,
    "question": "hacerles",
    "answer": "make them"
  },
  {
    "id": 3256,
    "question": "invita",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca nos invita a compartir las cosas.",
    "answer": "invites, encourages, invitation",
    "answerDetails": "She never invites us to share things."
  },
  {
    "id": 3257,
    "question": "habrán",
    "questionDetails": "Muchos ya te habrán dicho eso.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "I guess a lot of people have told you that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3258,
    "question": "técnica",
    "questionDetails": "El usa una extraña técnica.",
    "answer": "technique",
    "answerDetails": "He uses a strange technique."
  },
  {
    "id": 3259,
    "question": "huesos",
    "questionDetails": "Siempre que comemos pollo, al día siguiente hago un caldo con los huesos.",
    "answer": "carcass",
    "answerDetails": "Whenever we have chicken, I make a stock with the carcass the following Day."
  },
  {
    "id": 3260,
    "question": "pinche",
    "questionDetails": "Pinche aquí si necesita ayuda.",
    "answer": "click, scullion, puncture",
    "answerDetails": "Click here if you need assistance."
  },
  {
    "id": 3261,
    "question": "ana",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Mi madre se llama Ana!.",
    "answer": "anna",
    "answerDetails": "Anna is my mother’s name!."
  },
  {
    "id": 3262,
    "question": "autoridades",
    "questionDetails": "Hay autoridades más altas.",
    "answer": "authorities, officials",
    "answerDetails": "There are higher authorities."
  },
  {
    "id": 3263,
    "question": "fresco",
    "questionDetails": "Tomar un poco de aire fresco.",
    "answer": "fresh, cool, crisp",
    "answerDetails": "To get some fresh air."
  },
  {
    "id": 3264,
    "question": "garcía",
    "answer": "Garcia"
  },
  {
    "id": 3265,
    "question": "examen",
    "questionDetails": "A José le fue bien en el examen y será admitido a la maestría.",
    "answer": "examination",
    "answerDetails": "Jose did well on the examination and will be admitted to the Master’s program."
  },
  {
    "id": 3266,
    "question": "delincuente",
    "questionDetails": "Tu amigo era un delincuente.",
    "answer": "criminal",
    "answerDetails": "Your friend was a criminal."
  },
  {
    "id": 3267,
    "question": "veré",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando esté en Londres, veré Big Ben.",
    "answer": "i will see",
    "answerDetails": "When I am in London, I will see Big Ben."
  },
  {
    "id": 3268,
    "question": "pobrecito",
    "questionDetails": "El pobrecito no ha tenido nada para comer.",
    "answer": "poor fellow, poor",
    "answerDetails": "Poor fellow hasn’t had anything to eat."
  },
  {
    "id": 3269,
    "question": "aparezca",
    "questionDetails": "Debes hacer que aparezca en el lugar, …",
    "answer": "appears, displayed",
    "answerDetails": "You must make with that it appears in the place, …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3270,
    "question": "avisas",
    "answer": "Warn"
  },
  {
    "id": 3271,
    "question": "famosa",
    "questionDetails": "Llego a conversar con gente famosa como usted.",
    "answer": "famous",
    "answerDetails": "I get to talk to famous people like you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3272,
    "question": "acepta",
    "answer": "do you take"
  },
  {
    "id": 3273,
    "question": "manejando",
    "answer": "Driving"
  },
  {
    "id": 3274,
    "question": "temo",
    "questionDetails": "Me temo que podrías estar en lo cierto.",
    "answer": "fear, afraid, ‘m afraid",
    "answerDetails": "I fear you may be right."
  },
  {
    "id": 3275,
    "question": "despacito",
    "questionDetails": "Alguien me dijo despacito en el oído: “No te muevas”.",
    "answer": "softly",
    "answerDetails": "Someone said softly in my ear: “Don’t move.”."
  },
  {
    "id": 3276,
    "question": "caigo",
    "questionDetails": "Si yo caigo, todos caen conmigo.",
    "answer": "fall",
    "answerDetails": "I take the fall, everybody takes the fall."
  },
  {
    "id": 3277,
    "question": "plano",
    "questionDetails": "Si quieres tener el vientre plano, tienes que hacer abdominales.",
    "answer": "flat, blueprint",
    "answerDetails": "If you want a flat stomach, you have to do crunches."
  },
  {
    "id": 3278,
    "question": "prestar",
    "questionDetails": "¿Prestará la empresa el servicio de interpretación?",
    "answer": "provide, render",
    "answerDetails": "Will the company provide an interpreting service?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3279,
    "question": "temporada",
    "questionDetails": "La temporada de Cricket inglés está casi sobre nosotros.",
    "answer": "season, series",
    "answerDetails": "The English cricket season is almost upon us."
  },
  {
    "id": 3280,
    "question": "interesado",
    "questionDetails": "Estamos interesados en motivar a los alumnos a aprender idiomas.",
    "answer": "concerned, keen",
    "answerDetails": "We are concerned with encouraging students to learn foreign languages."
  },
  {
    "id": 3281,
    "question": "soportar",
    "questionDetails": "Existen metales que pueden soportar temperaturas enormemente elevadas.",
    "answer": "withstand, endure, abide",
    "answerDetails": "There are metals that can withstand tremendous heat."
  },
  {
    "id": 3282,
    "question": "hablaron",
    "questionDetails": "Los niños se metieron en problemas porque hablaron mientras lo hacía la profesora.",
    "answer": "they talked",
    "answerDetails": "The kids got in trouble because they talked while the teacher was talking."
  },
  {
    "id": 3283,
    "question": "decides",
    "questionDetails": "Tú decides a quién pertenece.",
    "answer": "decide",
    "answerDetails": "You decide who it belongs to."
  },
  {
    "id": 3284,
    "question": "soledad",
    "questionDetails": "La soledad de la granja.",
    "answer": "loneliness",
    "answerDetails": "The loneliness of the farm."
  },
  {
    "id": 3285,
    "question": "oídos",
    "questionDetails": "Pónganse esto en los oídos.",
    "answer": "ears, hearing",
    "answerDetails": "Put these in your ears."
  },
  {
    "id": 3286,
    "question": "pintura",
    "questionDetails": "Por fin terminé la pintura para mi clase de arte.",
    "answer": "painting",
    "answerDetails": "I finally finished the painting for my art class."
  },
  {
    "id": 3287,
    "question": "drama",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo querías ese drama.",
    "answer": "drama, tragedy",
    "answerDetails": "You just wanted that drama."
  },
  {
    "id": 3288,
    "question": "inventar",
    "questionDetails": "Con el tiempo, inventaron herramientas para facilitarse el trabajo.",
    "answer": "contrive",
    "answerDetails": "Eventually, they contrived some tools to make their work easier."
  },
  {
    "id": 3289,
    "question": "bajas",
    "questionDetails": "Las bajas sufridas durante la invasión de Normandía llegan a los cientos de miles.",
    "answer": "losses",
    "answerDetails": "The losses suffered during the invasion of Normandy are in the hundreds of thousands."
  },
  {
    "id": 3290,
    "question": "superar",
    "questionDetails": "Las acciones de la compañía superaron a las de la competencia.",
    "answer": "outperform",
    "answerDetails": "The company’s stock outperformed its competitors."
  },
  {
    "id": 3291,
    "question": "pierdas",
    "questionDetails": "No pierdas la esperanza.",
    "answer": "lose, miss, waste",
    "answerDetails": "Do not lose heart."
  },
  {
    "id": 3292,
    "question": "ganaste",
    "questionDetails": "Pero tú ganaste,y se hizo justicia.",
    "answer": "won, earned",
    "answerDetails": "But hey, you won, justice was done."
  },
  {
    "id": 3293,
    "question": "preferiría",
    "questionDetails": "Preferiría comer un gusano antes que darle un beso.",
    "answer": "i would rather",
    "answerDetails": "I would rather eat a worm than kiss him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3294,
    "question": "grabando",
    "questionDetails": "Sigue grabando y envíalo a la estación.",
    "answer": "recording, taping, videotaping",
    "answerDetails": "Just keep recording and sending it to the station."
  },
  {
    "id": 3295,
    "question": "explicarte",
    "questionDetails": "Puedo explicarte la escultura.",
    "answer": "explain",
    "answerDetails": "I can explain the statue."
  },
  {
    "id": 3296,
    "question": "queridos",
    "questionDetails": "Así como nuestros queridos hijos.",
    "answer": "dear, ones, darlings",
    "answerDetails": "As do our dear children."
  },
  {
    "id": 3297,
    "question": "independiente",
    "questionDetails": "La legislatura y la judicatura son independientes entre sí.",
    "answer": "independent, separate, freelance",
    "answerDetails": "The legislature and the judicature are independent of one another."
  },
  {
    "id": 3298,
    "question": "entendemos",
    "questionDetails": "Así que todos entendemos lo solo que se siente.",
    "answer": "understand",
    "answerDetails": "So we can all understand how lonely you must be."
  },
  {
    "id": 3299,
    "question": "enseño",
    "questionDetails": "Yo enseño esos cursos.",
    "answer": "teach, spanked",
    "answerDetails": "I teach those courses."
  },
  {
    "id": 3300,
    "question": "murieron",
    "answer": "Died"
  },
  {
    "id": 3301,
    "question": "tratan",
    "questionDetails": "Se tratan los síntomas, pero.",
    "answer": "treat, try, deal",
    "answerDetails": "They treat the symptoms, but."
  },
  {
    "id": 3302,
    "question": "tocaba",
    "questionDetails": "Tocaba el Chelo con tanta intensidad y estilo que ganó numerosos premios.",
    "answer": "she played, he was playing",
    "answerDetails": "She played the cello with such intensity and style that she won numerous prizes."
  },
  {
    "id": 3303,
    "question": "cayendo",
    "questionDetails": "Es como fichas de dominó cayendo.",
    "answer": "falling, dropping, tumbling",
    "answerDetails": "Like domino pieces falling."
  },
  {
    "id": 3304,
    "question": "gritando",
    "questionDetails": "Él estaba gritando muy alto.",
    "answer": "screaming, shouting, yelling",
    "answerDetails": "But he was just screaming so loud."
  },
  {
    "id": 3305,
    "question": "bolso",
    "questionDetails": "Su bolso y sus zapatos se coordinan.",
    "answer": "purse",
    "answerDetails": "Her purse and shoes match."
  },
  {
    "id": 3306,
    "question": "conocimiento",
    "questionDetails": "La transmisión del conocimiento.",
    "answer": "knowledge, understanding, consciousness",
    "answerDetails": "The transmission of knowledge."
  },
  {
    "id": 3307,
    "question": "elegido",
    "questionDetails": "No Estoy de acuerdo con los métodos elegidos por el alguacil, pero son efectivos.",
    "answer": "chosen, elected",
    "answerDetails": "I don’t agree with the sheriff’s chosen methods, but they are effective."
  },
  {
    "id": 3308,
    "question": "descubrí",
    "questionDetails": "Descubrí que mis padres fueron a Francia sin mí.",
    "answer": "i found out, i discovered",
    "answerDetails": "I found out that my parents went to France without me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3309,
    "question": "caminos",
    "questionDetails": "Dejen de viajar por los caminos.",
    "answer": "roads, paths, ways",
    "answerDetails": "Cease traveling on the roads."
  },
  {
    "id": 3310,
    "question": "pusimos",
    "questionDetails": "Y nosotros no la pusimos allí.",
    "answer": "put",
    "answerDetails": "And we did not put it there."
  },
  {
    "id": 3311,
    "question": "asustado",
    "questionDetails": "Estar asustado (a).",
    "answer": "scared, frightened, startled",
    "answerDetails": "To be scared."
  },
  {
    "id": 3312,
    "question": "esperado",
    "questionDetails": "Jamás me lo habría esperado de él.",
    "answer": "expected",
    "answerDetails": "I never expected that from him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3313,
    "question": "comen",
    "questionDetails": "Los peces comen materia podrida.",
    "answer": "eat, eaters",
    "answerDetails": "Fish eat decomposing matter."
  },
  {
    "id": 3314,
    "question": "quinto",
    "questionDetails": "Cuarto, puede ayudar al proceso de la revisión de la vida, y quinto, es una experiencia agradable y estimulante.",
    "answer": "fifth",
    "answerDetails": "Fourth, it can aid the process of life review, and fifth, it is an enjoyable and stimulating experience."
  },
  {
    "id": 3315,
    "question": "diego",
    "questionDetails": "¡ Hola! ¡ Me llamo Diego!.",
    "answer": "james",
    "answerDetails": "Hi! My name is James!."
  },
  {
    "id": 3316,
    "question": "negociar",
    "questionDetails": "Ustedes no tienen con qué negociar.",
    "answer": "bargain",
    "answerDetails": "You people have nothing to bargain with."
  },
  {
    "id": 3317,
    "question": "lópez",
    "answer": "Lopez"
  },
  {
    "id": 3318,
    "question": "respeta",
    "questionDetails": "Porque este es un grupo que respeta las buenas ideas.",
    "answer": "respects",
    "answerDetails": "Because this is a group that respects good ideas."
  },
  {
    "id": 3319,
    "question": "fíjese",
    "questionDetails": "Fíjese en este pezón.",
    "answer": "look",
    "answerDetails": "Look at this nipple."
  },
  {
    "id": 3320,
    "question": "eche",
    "questionDetails": "Es tiempo de que eche un vistazo.",
    "answer": "take, pour",
    "answerDetails": "Time for me to take in some sights."
  },
  {
    "id": 3321,
    "question": "comercial",
    "questionDetails": "Su trabajo es demasiado comercial.",
    "answer": "commercial, shopping, business",
    "answerDetails": "Their work is too commercial."
  },
  {
    "id": 3322,
    "question": "autorización",
    "questionDetails": "No podemos llevar a los alumnos de excursión sin la autorización de los padres.",
    "answer": "approval, authorization",
    "answerDetails": "We cannot take students on trips without parental approval."
  },
  {
    "id": 3323,
    "question": "parió",
    "questionDetails": "¡La madre que me parió!",
    "answer": "bore",
    "answerDetails": "The mother who bore me!"
  },
  {
    "id": 3324,
    "question": "c",
    "answer": "C, w"
  },
  {
    "id": 3325,
    "question": "equivocada",
    "questionDetails": "Has tomado la vida equivocada.",
    "answer": "wrong, mistaken, misguided",
    "answerDetails": "You take the wrong life."
  },
  {
    "id": 3326,
    "question": "ruego",
    "questionDetails": "El jefe escuchó los ruegos de Javier y le dio una segunda oportunidad antes de despedirlo.",
    "answer": "plea",
    "answerDetails": "The boss heard Javier’s pleas and gave him a second chance before firing him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3327,
    "question": "resultó",
    "questionDetails": "¿Terminaste tu pintura?-Sí, resultó fantástica.",
    "answer": "it turned out",
    "answerDetails": "Did you finish your painting?-Yes, it turned out fantastic."
  },
  {
    "id": 3328,
    "question": "bestia",
    "questionDetails": "No sé cómo soporta estar casada con ese bestia.",
    "answer": "beast",
    "answerDetails": "I don’t know how she stands being married to that beast."
  },
  {
    "id": 3329,
    "question": "i",
    "answer": "I"
  },
  {
    "id": 3330,
    "question": "contarme",
    "questionDetails": "Iba a contarme su teoría.",
    "answer": "tell me",
    "answerDetails": "You were about to tell me your theory."
  },
  {
    "id": 3331,
    "question": "china",
    "answer": "China, Chinese"
  },
  {
    "id": 3332,
    "question": "pasta",
    "questionDetails": "Mezcla el agua y el polvo hasta que formen una pasta.",
    "answer": "paste, dough, pulp",
    "answerDetails": "Mix the water and the powder until they form a paste."
  },
  {
    "id": 3333,
    "question": "estarías",
    "questionDetails": "Tú también estarías cansado si hubieses cuidado al bebé todo el día.",
    "answer": "you would be",
    "answerDetails": "You would be tired too if you had taken care of the baby all Day."
  },
  {
    "id": 3334,
    "question": "discusión",
    "questionDetails": "Supongamos, por el bien de la discusión, que esta es la posición legal.",
    "answer": "argument, debate",
    "answerDetails": "Suppose, for the sake of argument, that this is the legal position."
  },
  {
    "id": 3335,
    "question": "maestra",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes usar esta llave maestra.",
    "answer": "master",
    "answerDetails": "You could use this master key."
  },
  {
    "id": 3336,
    "question": "refiere",
    "questionDetails": "refiere el momento en el que se golpea la cuerda,",
    "answer": "refers, relates",
    "answerDetails": "refers to the moment in which the string is hammered,"
  },
  {
    "id": 3337,
    "question": "listas",
    "questionDetails": "También pueden crear listas de reproducción.",
    "answer": "lists, ready, playlists",
    "answerDetails": "You can also create play lists."
  },
  {
    "id": 3338,
    "question": "recibo",
    "questionDetails": "Necesito pagar el recibo de la luz al más tardar mañana o se nos cortará el servicio.",
    "answer": "bill",
    "answerDetails": "I need to pay the electric bill by tomorrow or our service will be cut."
  },
  {
    "id": 3339,
    "question": "ofrezco",
    "questionDetails": "Te ofrezco la paz entre nuestros pueblos.",
    "answer": "offer",
    "answerDetails": "I offer peace between our people."
  },
  {
    "id": 3340,
    "question": "tomaste",
    "questionDetails": "Tomaste me lugar.-No Deberías haberte movido.",
    "answer": "you took",
    "answerDetails": "You took my seat.-You shouldn’t have moved."
  },
  {
    "id": 3341,
    "question": "canto",
    "questionDetails": "Clases de canto.",
    "answer": "singing, chant, hymn",
    "answerDetails": "Singing lessons."
  },
  {
    "id": 3342,
    "question": "empleado",
    "questionDetails": "Estuve empleado en mi último trabajo por 5 años antes de renunciar.",
    "answer": "employed",
    "answerDetails": "I was employed with my last job for five years before I quit."
  },
  {
    "id": 3343,
    "question": "gane",
    "questionDetails": "Tiempo de que gane.",
    "answer": "win, earn, gain",
    "answerDetails": "Time for me to win."
  },
  {
    "id": 3344,
    "question": "molestia",
    "questionDetails": "Un nervio pinzado en la espalda me viene causando muchísimas molestias.",
    "answer": "discomfort, nuisance, annoyance",
    "answerDetails": "A pinched nerve in my back has been causing me a great deal of discomfort."
  },
  {
    "id": 3345,
    "question": "cambiaron",
    "questionDetails": "Atributos que la cambiaron.",
    "answer": "changed, shifted, switched",
    "answerDetails": "Attributes that changed her."
  },
  {
    "id": 3346,
    "question": "faltó",
    "questionDetails": "Quizá nos faltó un paso.",
    "answer": "missed, disrespected, lacked",
    "answerDetails": "Maybe we missed a step."
  },
  {
    "id": 3347,
    "question": "interrumpir",
    "questionDetails": "Estamos instándoles a interrumpir el suministro de armas a las fuerzas rebeldes.",
    "answer": "discontinue, disrupt",
    "answerDetails": "We are urging them to discontinue the provision of arms to the rebels."
  },
  {
    "id": 3348,
    "question": "tuyas",
    "questionDetails": "Mis opciones son mucho más limitadas que las tuyas.",
    "answer": "yours",
    "answerDetails": "My choices are much more limited than yours."
  },
  {
    "id": 3349,
    "question": "volvieron",
    "questionDetails": "Justin y su familia se mudaron el año pasado pero volvieron de visita.",
    "answer": "they returned",
    "answerDetails": "Justin and his family moved last year, but they returned for a visit."
  },
  {
    "id": 3350,
    "question": "terminando",
    "questionDetails": "Se está terminando, toda esta época de nuestras vidas.",
    "answer": "ending, finishing, terminating",
    "answerDetails": "This is all ending, this time of our lives."
  },
  {
    "id": 3351,
    "question": "quitado",
    "questionDetails": "Todo lo que me causó dolor fue quitado.",
    "answer": "removed",
    "answerDetails": "All that caused me grief was removed."
  },
  {
    "id": 3352,
    "question": "coincidencia",
    "questionDetails": "La coincidencia de interés entre las empresas mineras y ciertos políticos.",
    "answer": "coincidence",
    "answerDetails": "The coincidence of interest between the mining companies and certain politicians."
  },
  {
    "id": 3353,
    "question": "imaginaba",
    "questionDetails": "Me imaginaba diferente este lugar.",
    "answer": "imagined, figured, pictured",
    "answerDetails": "I imagined this place differently."
  },
  {
    "id": 3354,
    "question": "gas",
    "questionDetails": "A menos que enviemos el gas.",
    "answer": "gas",
    "answerDetails": "Unless we send over the gas."
  },
  {
    "id": 3355,
    "question": "parezco",
    "questionDetails": "No me parezco a mamá en nada.",
    "answer": "look, resemble",
    "answerDetails": "I look nothing like my mother."
  },
  {
    "id": 3356,
    "question": "emociones",
    "questionDetails": "Significa soltar sus emociones.",
    "answer": "emotions, thrills, excitement",
    "answerDetails": "To express your emotions."
  },
  {
    "id": 3357,
    "question": "haberse",
    "questionDetails": "Debe haberse imaginado que lo entrega rías.",
    "answer": "have",
    "answerDetails": "He must have figured you’d turn him in."
  },
  {
    "id": 3358,
    "question": "arregla",
    "questionDetails": "Ella trabaja para él, le arregla las reuniones.",
    "answer": "arranges, fix, manages",
    "answerDetails": "She takes orders for him, arranges meets."
  },
  {
    "id": 3359,
    "question": "terror",
    "questionDetails": "Nancy tiene terror a los Aviones.",
    "answer": "horror, dread",
    "answerDetails": "Nancy has a horror of airplanes."
  },
  {
    "id": 3360,
    "question": "madera",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca he, golpear a la madera, ha sido encasillado.",
    "answer": "wood, lumber",
    "answerDetails": "I have never, knock on wood, been typecast."
  },
  {
    "id": 3361,
    "question": "funcionan",
    "questionDetails": "Entender cómo funcionan las cosas.",
    "answer": "work, operate, function",
    "answerDetails": "Understanding how things work."
  },
  {
    "id": 3362,
    "question": "dámelo",
    "answer": "Give it to me"
  },
  {
    "id": 3363,
    "question": "verano",
    "questionDetails": "En verano.",
    "answer": "summer",
    "answerDetails": "In (the) summer."
  },
  {
    "id": 3364,
    "question": "comemos",
    "questionDetails": "Comemos en media hora.",
    "answer": "eat",
    "answerDetails": "We can eat in half an hour."
  },
  {
    "id": 3365,
    "question": "generación",
    "questionDetails": "El crecimiento económico tuvo un impacto en la generación de puestos de trabajo.",
    "answer": "generation",
    "answerDetails": "Economic growth had an impact on the generation of jobs."
  },
  {
    "id": 3366,
    "question": "pilas",
    "questionDetails": "Pero ellos no tienen las pilas.",
    "answer": "batteries, piles, stacks",
    "answerDetails": "But they don’t have the batteries."
  },
  {
    "id": 3367,
    "question": "perdóneme",
    "questionDetails": "Perdóneme. ¿Me puede dar su hora?",
    "answer": "pardon me",
    "answerDetails": "Pardon me. Do you have the time?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3368,
    "question": "mataste",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca pensé que tú lo mataste.",
    "answer": "killed, murdered",
    "answerDetails": "I never thought you killed him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3369,
    "question": "agencia",
    "questionDetails": "La Agencia de Protección ambiental.",
    "answer": "agency",
    "answerDetails": "The Environmental Protection Agency."
  },
  {
    "id": 3370,
    "question": "chance",
    "questionDetails": "¿Conoces a alguien en esta ciudad que haya ganado el chance?",
    "answer": "lottery",
    "answerDetails": "Do you know anyone in this city who has won the lottery?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3371,
    "question": "suplico",
    "questionDetails": "Te suplico que la sigas buscando.",
    "answer": "beg, entreat, implore",
    "answerDetails": "I beg of you to carry on."
  },
  {
    "id": 3372,
    "question": "nieto",
    "questionDetails": "Mi nieto no tiene más familia.",
    "answer": "grandson",
    "answerDetails": "My grandson only has me left."
  },
  {
    "id": 3373,
    "question": "argentina",
    "answer": "Argentina"
  },
  {
    "id": 3374,
    "question": "vais",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que vais a perder.",
    "answer": "‘re going, going",
    "answerDetails": "I think you’re going to lose."
  },
  {
    "id": 3375,
    "question": "tristeza",
    "questionDetails": "Y es natural que la tristeza confunda los sentimientos.",
    "answer": "sorrow",
    "answerDetails": "It is also natural that sorrow mixes up feelings."
  },
  {
    "id": 3376,
    "question": "cuartos",
    "questionDetails": "Los cuartos de confinamiento están justo debajo de nosotros.",
    "answer": "quarters, rooms, fourths",
    "answerDetails": "The confinement quarters are on the floors just below us."
  },
  {
    "id": 3377,
    "question": "vestida",
    "questionDetails": "Y estaba vestida en túnicas de fina seda.",
    "answer": "dressed, clothed, arrayed",
    "answerDetails": "And she was dressed in flowing gowns of sheer silk."
  },
  {
    "id": 3378,
    "question": "fama",
    "questionDetails": "El pueblo es el lugar de nacimiento de la señora Beeton, de la fama de la cocina.",
    "answer": "fame",
    "answerDetails": "The village is the birthplace of Mrs Beeton, of cookery fame."
  },
  {
    "id": 3379,
    "question": "tenerte",
    "answer": "have you"
  },
  {
    "id": 3380,
    "question": "vigilando",
    "questionDetails": "Vi al sheriff fuera vigilando su casa.",
    "answer": "watching, staking out, guarding",
    "answerDetails": "I saw the sheriff outside watching your house."
  },
  {
    "id": 3381,
    "question": "cantando",
    "questionDetails": "Yo quería trompetas doradas y ángeles cantando.",
    "answer": "singing, singin’, chanting",
    "answerDetails": "I wanted golden trumpets and angels singing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3382,
    "question": "estuvieras",
    "questionDetails": "Me gustaría que estuvieras aquí.",
    "answer": "were",
    "answerDetails": "I just wish you were here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3383,
    "question": "oficio",
    "questionDetails": "Mi abuelo me enseñó el oficio tradicional de carpintería.",
    "answer": "craft",
    "answerDetails": "My grandfather taught me the traditional craft of woodworking."
  },
  {
    "id": 3384,
    "question": "estrés",
    "questionDetails": "Estar sometido (a) a mucho estrés.",
    "answer": "stress",
    "answerDetails": "To be under a lot of stress."
  },
  {
    "id": 3385,
    "question": "confirmado",
    "questionDetails": "Tu amigo ha confirmado tu versión.",
    "answer": "confirmed",
    "answerDetails": "Your friend confirmed your story."
  },
  {
    "id": 3386,
    "question": "cartera",
    "questionDetails": "No llevo efectivo en mi cartera.",
    "answer": "wallet, purse",
    "answerDetails": "I don’t have any cash in my wallet."
  },
  {
    "id": 3387,
    "question": "jode",
    "questionDetails": "Pues ahora jode con tu cabeza.",
    "answer": "screwing, sucks, bothers",
    "answerDetails": "Well, now he’s screwing with your head."
  },
  {
    "id": 3388,
    "question": "encontrarlo",
    "questionDetails": "Perdí mi libro de texto.-Si no puedes encontrarlo, tendrás que comprar uno nuevo.",
    "answer": "find it",
    "answerDetails": "I lost my textbook.-If you can’t find it, you’ll need to buy a new one."
  },
  {
    "id": 3389,
    "question": "conoció",
    "questionDetails": "La novia de Diego se llama Siabhon. La conoció en Irlanda.",
    "answer": "he met her, she met him, she knew",
    "answerDetails": "Diego’s girlfriend’s name is Siabhon. He met her in Ireland."
  },
  {
    "id": 3390,
    "question": "desesperada",
    "questionDetails": "Ésta es nuestra hora más desesperada.",
    "answer": "desperate, hopeless, desperately",
    "answerDetails": "This is our most desperate hour."
  },
  {
    "id": 3391,
    "question": "coches",
    "questionDetails": "Han movido los coches.",
    "answer": "cars, coaches",
    "answerDetails": "They moved the cars."
  },
  {
    "id": 3392,
    "question": "llevaste",
    "questionDetails": "Así que lo llevaste contigo.",
    "answer": "took",
    "answerDetails": "So you took it with you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3393,
    "question": "adultos",
    "questionDetails": "Una caja de arena para adultos con dinero.",
    "answer": "adults, grownups, grown",
    "answerDetails": "A sandbox for adults with money."
  },
  {
    "id": 3394,
    "question": "bajando",
    "questionDetails": "Estamos bajando el escudo.",
    "answer": "lowering, dropping, down",
    "answerDetails": "We are lowering the shield."
  },
  {
    "id": 3395,
    "question": "hayamos",
    "questionDetails": "No me creo que hayamos rodado aquí todo el día.",
    "answer": "we",
    "answerDetails": "I cannot believe we filmed here all day."
  },
  {
    "id": 3396,
    "question": "extranjero",
    "questionDetails": "Militares que regresan desde el extranjero.",
    "answer": "abroad, foreign",
    "answerDetails": "Servicemen returning from abroad."
  },
  {
    "id": 3397,
    "question": "quedará",
    "questionDetails": "En ese caso, se quedará aquí.",
    "answer": "stay",
    "answerDetails": "In that case, you will stay here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3398,
    "question": "mentido",
    "questionDetails": "Has mentido a esta gente.",
    "answer": "lied",
    "answerDetails": "You lied to these people."
  },
  {
    "id": 3399,
    "question": "demasiadas",
    "questionDetails": "Me temo que está asumiendo demasiadas cosas.",
    "answer": "too much",
    "answerDetails": "I am afraid you assumed too much."
  },
  {
    "id": 3400,
    "question": "labor",
    "questionDetails": "La ONG ha llevado a cabo una labor humanitaria indispensable en África.",
    "answer": "work, task, job",
    "answerDetails": "The NGO has carried out indispensable humanitarian work in Africa."
  },
  {
    "id": 3401,
    "question": "aparecen",
    "questionDetails": "Los vampiros aparecen solo de noche.",
    "answer": "appear, listed, displayed",
    "answerDetails": "Vampires appear only night."
  },
  {
    "id": 3402,
    "question": "pares",
    "questionDetails": "Ayer ella dejó dos pares de zapatos bajo la silla.",
    "answer": "pairs, peers, torques",
    "answerDetails": "Yesterday she left two pairs of shoes under the chair."
  },
  {
    "id": 3403,
    "question": "práctica",
    "questionDetails": "La teoría es sencilla. Es otra cosa llevarla a la práctica.",
    "answer": "practice",
    "answerDetails": "The theory is easy. Putting it into practice is another matter."
  },
  {
    "id": 3404,
    "question": "podrán",
    "questionDetails": "Los niños podrán jugar aquí dentro todos los días.",
    "answer": "can",
    "answerDetails": "The children can play in here every day."
  },
  {
    "id": 3405,
    "question": "clima",
    "questionDetails": "En esta compañía nuestra meta es establecer un clima de confianza.",
    "answer": "climate, weather, atmosphere",
    "answerDetails": "At this company our aim is to build a climate of trust."
  },
  {
    "id": 3406,
    "question": "origen",
    "questionDetails": "Su teoría del origen de la vida.",
    "answer": "origin",
    "answerDetails": "His theory of the origin of life."
  },
  {
    "id": 3407,
    "question": "rápida",
    "questionDetails": "Tenía planeada una rápida cremación.",
    "answer": "quick, fast, rapid",
    "answerDetails": "Had a quick cremation all planned."
  },
  {
    "id": 3408,
    "question": "existencia",
    "questionDetails": "Pero tenéis que guardar en secreto nuestra existencia.",
    "answer": "existence",
    "answerDetails": "But you have to keep our existence secret."
  },
  {
    "id": 3409,
    "question": "preguntaba",
    "questionDetails": "Cada año en la escuela religiosa, preguntaba cómo Dios podía dejar que la humanidad sufra.",
    "answer": "i asked",
    "answerDetails": "Every year in religious school, I asked how God could allow suffering."
  },
  {
    "id": 3410,
    "question": "vení",
    "questionDetails": "Vení a buscarla si querés.",
    "answer": "come",
    "answerDetails": "Come and get her if you want her."
  },
  {
    "id": 3411,
    "question": "santiago",
    "questionDetails": "Mis padres me iban a llamar Santiago, pero escogieron Juan en vez.",
    "answer": "james",
    "answerDetails": "My parents were going to name me James, but chose John instead."
  },
  {
    "id": 3412,
    "question": "compadre",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero un hot dog con todo, compadre.",
    "answer": "bro",
    "answerDetails": "I’ll take a hot dog with everything, bro."
  },
  {
    "id": 3413,
    "question": "regrese",
    "answer": "he comes back"
  },
  {
    "id": 3414,
    "question": "semejante",
    "questionDetails": "La calidad es semejante a la que encontrarías en otros sitios.",
    "answer": "similar, such, akin",
    "answerDetails": "The quality is similar to what you might find at other places."
  },
  {
    "id": 3415,
    "question": "presentación",
    "questionDetails": "La presentación de Fernanda sobre los hombres lobo fue muy informativa.",
    "answer": "presentation, submission, filing",
    "answerDetails": "Fernanda’s presentation on werewolves was very informative."
  },
  {
    "id": 3416,
    "question": "quédese",
    "questionDetails": "Quédese junto a mí y lo haremos juntos.",
    "answer": "stay, stick around",
    "answerDetails": "Stay by me and we’ll take it together."
  },
  {
    "id": 3417,
    "question": "enojada",
    "questionDetails": "Estaba enojada con mi papá una noche antes.",
    "answer": "angry, mad, upset",
    "answerDetails": "She was angry with my dad the night before."
  },
  {
    "id": 3418,
    "question": "solita",
    "questionDetails": "Mírate, aquí, toda solita.",
    "answer": "alone",
    "answerDetails": "Look at you all alone in here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3419,
    "question": "embarazo",
    "questionDetails": "Fumar durante el embarazo aumenta las probabilidades de un parto prematuro.",
    "answer": "pregnancy",
    "answerDetails": "Smoking during pregnancy increases the chances of a preterm delivery."
  },
  {
    "id": 3420,
    "question": "sintiendo",
    "questionDetails": "Ya debería estar sintiendo algo.",
    "answer": "feeling, sensing, feelin’",
    "answerDetails": "She should be feeling something by now."
  },
  {
    "id": 3421,
    "question": "divorcio",
    "questionDetails": "Emprender los trámites de divorcio (contra alguien).",
    "answer": "divorce",
    "answerDetails": "To start divorce proceedings (against somebody)."
  },
  {
    "id": 3422,
    "question": "feria",
    "questionDetails": "Necesitamos preparar nuestro material para la feria comercial.",
    "answer": "fair, exhibition",
    "answerDetails": "We need to prepare our materials for the trade fair."
  },
  {
    "id": 3423,
    "question": "déjenme",
    "questionDetails": "Entonces déjenme incrementar la temperatura.",
    "answer": "let me",
    "answerDetails": "So now let me increase the temperature."
  },
  {
    "id": 3424,
    "question": "delincuentes",
    "questionDetails": "Trabaja con delincuentes juveniles.",
    "answer": "offenders, criminals, delinquents",
    "answerDetails": "He works with juvenile offenders."
  },
  {
    "id": 3425,
    "question": "jefes",
    "questionDetails": "Estamos robando a nuestros propios jefes.",
    "answer": "chiefs, bosses, heads",
    "answerDetails": "We are stealing from our own chiefs."
  },
  {
    "id": 3426,
    "question": "miserable",
    "questionDetails": "Después de la muerte de sus hijos, su miserable existencia se volvió casi insoportable.",
    "answer": "wretched, paltry",
    "answerDetails": "After the death of his children, his wretched existence became almost unbearable."
  },
  {
    "id": 3427,
    "question": "entrego",
    "questionDetails": "Me entrego a usted.",
    "answer": "give",
    "answerDetails": "I give you myself."
  },
  {
    "id": 3428,
    "question": "quisiste",
    "questionDetails": "Realmente nunca quisiste que ganara.",
    "answer": "wanted",
    "answerDetails": "You never really wanted me to win."
  },
  {
    "id": 3429,
    "question": "ocupo",
    "questionDetails": "Yo me ocupo de todo aquí.",
    "answer": "take care",
    "answerDetails": "I take care of everything around here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3430,
    "question": "iré",
    "questionDetails": "¡ La cena está lista!-Iré en un minuto.",
    "answer": "i will come, i am coming",
    "answerDetails": "Dinner is ready!-I will come in a minute."
  },
  {
    "id": 3431,
    "question": "sospecha",
    "questionDetails": "La policía arrestó a la pandilla bajo sospecha de homicidio.",
    "answer": "suspicion",
    "answerDetails": "The police arrested the gang on suspicion of murder."
  },
  {
    "id": 3432,
    "question": "fallar",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes fallar o puedes volar.",
    "answer": "fail",
    "answerDetails": "You may fail or you may fly."
  },
  {
    "id": 3433,
    "question": "funcionó",
    "answer": "Worked"
  },
  {
    "id": 3434,
    "question": "evidente",
    "questionDetails": "Era evidente por sus comentarios en clase que no se había terminado el libro.",
    "answer": "evident, clear, apparent",
    "answerDetails": "It was evident from her comments in class that she hadn’t finished the book."
  },
  {
    "id": 3435,
    "question": "quedarnos",
    "questionDetails": "Quedarnos en la cama todo el día.",
    "answer": "stay",
    "answerDetails": "Stay in bed together all day."
  },
  {
    "id": 3436,
    "question": "llevarla",
    "questionDetails": "Mi hija está enferma. Tengo que llevarla al médico.",
    "answer": "take her",
    "answerDetails": "My daughter is sick. I need to take her to the doctor."
  },
  {
    "id": 3437,
    "question": "análisis",
    "questionDetails": "El análisis de la situación económica de la empresa mostró que necesitaban buscar inversores lo antes posible.",
    "answer": "review, test, exploration",
    "answerDetails": "The review of the company’s financial situation showed that they needed to look for investors as soon as possible."
  },
  {
    "id": 3438,
    "question": "queso",
    "questionDetails": "Tambien por su queso.",
    "answer": "cheese",
    "answerDetails": "Also for their cheese."
  },
  {
    "id": 3439,
    "question": "dejara",
    "questionDetails": "Tu madre me dijo que te dejara en paz.",
    "answer": "leave",
    "answerDetails": "Your mother told me to leave you alone."
  },
  {
    "id": 3440,
    "question": "atentos",
    "questionDetails": "La razón es que tus espíritus están atentos.",
    "answer": "attentive, vigilant, tuned",
    "answerDetails": "The reason is your spirits are attentive."
  },
  {
    "id": 3441,
    "question": "costar",
    "questionDetails": "El viaje le costará £ 25.",
    "answer": "cost",
    "answerDetails": "The journey will cost her £25."
  },
  {
    "id": 3442,
    "question": "quedara",
    "questionDetails": "Quería que se quedara.",
    "answer": "stay, stick around",
    "answerDetails": "I wanted him to stay."
  },
  {
    "id": 3443,
    "question": "salvaje",
    "questionDetails": "Actuando en Hollywood estaba más allá de mis sueños más salvajes.",
    "answer": "wild, savage, feral",
    "answerDetails": "Performing in Hollywood was beyond my wildest dreams."
  },
  {
    "id": 3444,
    "question": "útil",
    "questionDetails": "Aspirinas son útiles para dolores de cabeza.",
    "answer": "useful, helpful, handy",
    "answerDetails": "Aspirins are useful for headaches."
  },
  {
    "id": 3445,
    "question": "disfruta",
    "questionDetails": "Jessica está feliz aquí en el estudio porque disfruta cantando.",
    "answer": "she enjoys",
    "answerDetails": "Jessica is happy here in the studio because she enjoys singing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3446,
    "question": "cumplo",
    "questionDetails": "Yo cumplo mi parte del trato.",
    "answer": "keep",
    "answerDetails": "I keep my end of the deal, old friend."
  },
  {
    "id": 3447,
    "question": "rostro",
    "questionDetails": "La expresión de su rostro lo decía todo.",
    "answer": "face, countenance",
    "answerDetails": "The expression on her face said it all."
  },
  {
    "id": 3448,
    "question": "contamos",
    "questionDetails": "Nos ofrecimos como voluntarios en una escuela primaria ayer. Les contamos chistes a los niños y jugamos con ellos.",
    "answer": "we told",
    "answerDetails": "We volunteered at an elementary school yesterday. We told the kids jokes and played with them."
  },
  {
    "id": 3449,
    "question": "juzgar",
    "questionDetails": "No se puede juzgar sus propios juegos .",
    "answer": "judge",
    "answerDetails": "You can not judge their own games."
  },
  {
    "id": 3450,
    "question": "acercar",
    "questionDetails": "Usted tiene aquí, si se puede acercar una cámara.",
    "answer": "approach",
    "answerDetails": "You have here, if we can approach a camera."
  },
  {
    "id": 3451,
    "question": "extra",
    "questionDetails": "Supongo que puede esperar a tu extra.",
    "answer": "bonus",
    "answerDetails": "I guess it can wait till bonus time."
  },
  {
    "id": 3452,
    "question": "preguntes",
    "questionDetails": "Estaba esperando que lo preguntes.",
    "answer": "ask",
    "answerDetails": "I was waiting for you to ask."
  },
  {
    "id": 3453,
    "question": "comenzó",
    "questionDetails": "Comenzó su carrera de profesor hace 30 años.",
    "answer": "he began, she started",
    "answerDetails": "He began his career as a teacher 30 years ago."
  },
  {
    "id": 3454,
    "question": "fuese",
    "questionDetails": "Puede que no, si fuese un secreto.",
    "answer": "was",
    "answerDetails": "Maybe not if it was a secret."
  },
  {
    "id": 3455,
    "question": "antigua",
    "questionDetails": "Una ciudad justa, y una antigua y gloriosa.",
    "answer": "ancient, old, former",
    "answerDetails": "A fair city, and an ancient and glorious one."
  },
  {
    "id": 3456,
    "question": "entraron",
    "questionDetails": "Y los vecinos entraron el mismo año.",
    "answer": "entered",
    "answerDetails": "And the neighbors entered the same year."
  },
  {
    "id": 3457,
    "question": "cambié",
    "questionDetails": "Lo cambié a marcos.",
    "answer": "changed, switched, swapped",
    "answerDetails": "I have changed it into marks."
  },
  {
    "id": 3458,
    "question": "encarga",
    "questionDetails": "Quién se encarga de garantizar que el sitio mantiene …",
    "answer": "responsible, handles, charge",
    "answerDetails": "Who is responsible for ensuring that the site holds …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3459,
    "question": "fijo",
    "questionDetails": "Gastos fijos.",
    "answer": "fixed, steady",
    "answerDetails": "Fixed expenses."
  },
  {
    "id": 3460,
    "question": "permiten",
    "questionDetails": "Cargas que nos permiten.",
    "answer": "allow, enable, permit",
    "answerDetails": "Burdens that allow us."
  },
  {
    "id": 3461,
    "question": "señales",
    "questionDetails": "Bueno, tienes que aprender sus señales.",
    "answer": "signals, cues, landmarks",
    "answerDetails": "You have to learn their signals."
  },
  {
    "id": 3462,
    "question": "duros",
    "questionDetails": "Se tienen reflejos breves y duros de todo.",
    "answer": "hard, tough, harsh",
    "answerDetails": "You get really short, hard reflections off everything."
  },
  {
    "id": 3463,
    "question": "bolsillo",
    "questionDetails": "Ella lo vio bloquear y el bolsillo de la llave.",
    "answer": "pocket",
    "answerDetails": "She watched him lock up and pocket the key."
  },
  {
    "id": 3464,
    "question": "cuantos",
    "questionDetails": "Lo que necesitas es unos cuantos dias de prision.",
    "answer": "few",
    "answerDetails": "What you need is a few days in prison."
  },
  {
    "id": 3465,
    "question": "decido",
    "questionDetails": "Yo decido si nos quedamos o no.",
    "answer": "decide",
    "answerDetails": "I decide whether we stay or not."
  },
  {
    "id": 3466,
    "question": "horario",
    "questionDetails": "Necesitaremos el horario de trenes para planear nuestro viaje.",
    "answer": "schedule, hours",
    "answerDetails": "We will need the train schedule to plan our trip."
  },
  {
    "id": 3467,
    "question": "vacía",
    "answer": "empty, void, blank"
  },
  {
    "id": 3468,
    "question": "desperté",
    "questionDetails": "Trate de detenerlo y me desperté quince minutos despues.",
    "answer": "woke up, awoke, woke",
    "answerDetails": "I tried to stop him and woke up fifteen minutes later."
  },
  {
    "id": 3469,
    "question": "oscuridad",
    "questionDetails": "La oscuridad de su chaqueta.",
    "answer": "darkness, obscurity, blackness",
    "answerDetails": "The darkness of his jacket."
  },
  {
    "id": 3470,
    "question": "convertirse",
    "answer": "develop, become, converted"
  },
  {
    "id": 3471,
    "question": "apoyar",
    "questionDetails": "No voy a apoyar ninguna estrategia que sea perjudicial para el desarrollo económico.",
    "answer": "endorse",
    "answerDetails": "I’m not going to endorse any strategy that would be detrimental to economic growth."
  },
  {
    "id": 3472,
    "question": "putas",
    "questionDetails": "Tu y tus putas salgan de nuestra propiedad.",
    "answer": "whores, hookers, bitches",
    "answerDetails": "You and your whores get off of our property."
  },
  {
    "id": 3473,
    "question": "agenda",
    "questionDetails": "Intentaré hacerte un hueco, pero tengo la agenda algo justa.",
    "answer": "schedule, calendar",
    "answerDetails": "I’ll try to squeeze you in, but my schedule is pretty tight."
  },
  {
    "id": 3474,
    "question": "mina",
    "questionDetails": "No hay mucho oxígeno en la profunda mina, por eso los trabajadores deben tomar descansos frecuentes.",
    "answer": "mine, pit",
    "answerDetails": "There is not much oxygen in the deep mine, so the workers must take frequent breaks."
  },
  {
    "id": 3475,
    "question": "cómplice",
    "questionDetails": "A Lucy la hallaron culpable de ser una cómplice del delito.",
    "answer": "accessory",
    "answerDetails": "Lucy was found guilty of being an accessory to the crime."
  },
  {
    "id": 3476,
    "question": "alcanzo",
    "questionDetails": "alcanzo el numero uno en las listas.",
    "answer": "reached",
    "answerDetails": "reached number one in the charts."
  },
  {
    "id": 3477,
    "question": "trate",
    "questionDetails": "Trate de no cerrar los ojos.",
    "answer": "try, concerned, treat",
    "answerDetails": "Try not to close your eyes."
  },
  {
    "id": 3478,
    "question": "honesto",
    "questionDetails": "Para ser honesto, esperaba jugar peor.",
    "answer": "honest",
    "answerDetails": "To be honest, I expected to play worse."
  },
  {
    "id": 3479,
    "question": "miel",
    "questionDetails": "La miel la hacen las abejas usando el néctar de las flores.",
    "answer": "honey",
    "answerDetails": "Honey is made by bees using the nectar of flowers."
  },
  {
    "id": 3480,
    "question": "valió",
    "questionDetails": "lo que le valió la reputación",
    "answer": "earned",
    "answerDetails": "which earned him the reputation"
  },
  {
    "id": 3481,
    "question": "lógico",
    "questionDetails": "Porque el único movimiento lógico es dejarle fuera.",
    "answer": "logical",
    "answerDetails": "Because the only logical move is to shut him out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3482,
    "question": "olvídalo",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo muchas ganas de verte en un disfraz de payaso.-Olvídalo. No va a pasar.",
    "answer": "forget it",
    "answerDetails": "I’m looking forward to seeing you in a clown costume.-Forget it. It’s not going to happen."
  },
  {
    "id": 3483,
    "question": "andando",
    "questionDetails": "Iba andando a la escuela.",
    "answer": "walk, ticking",
    "answerDetails": "I had to walk to school."
  },
  {
    "id": 3484,
    "question": "confías",
    "questionDetails": "Sé que no confías en nadie.",
    "answer": "trust, confide",
    "answerDetails": "I know you don’t trust anyone."
  },
  {
    "id": 3485,
    "question": "payaso",
    "questionDetails": "Harvey se hizo el payaso simulando ser un perro.",
    "answer": "clown",
    "answerDetails": "Harvey clowned around pretending to be a dog."
  },
  {
    "id": 3486,
    "question": "retirar",
    "questionDetails": "Se negó a retirar lo dicho, abocando a ambas partes a un callejón sin salida.",
    "answer": "retract",
    "answerDetails": "She refused to retract what she had said, causing an impasse between the two sides."
  },
  {
    "id": 3487,
    "question": "lleguemos",
    "questionDetails": "No hasta que lleguemos allí.",
    "answer": "get",
    "answerDetails": "Not until we get there."
  },
  {
    "id": 3488,
    "question": "acompáñame",
    "questionDetails": "Me voy a almorzar. ¡ Acompáñame!.",
    "answer": "join me",
    "answerDetails": "I’m on my way to get lunch. Join me!."
  },
  {
    "id": 3489,
    "question": "aprovechando",
    "questionDetails": "Te estás aprovechando de esa gente.",
    "answer": "taking advantage, leveraging, benefitting from",
    "answerDetails": "You are taking advantage of these people."
  },
  {
    "id": 3490,
    "question": "dolores",
    "questionDetails": "Reduce los gases y los dolores abdominales.",
    "answer": "pains, aches, sorrows",
    "answerDetails": "It reduce gas and abdominal pains."
  },
  {
    "id": 3491,
    "question": "arreglamos",
    "answer": "Unbreak, fix"
  },
  {
    "id": 3492,
    "question": "conocerla",
    "questionDetails": "Me alegro de conocerla.",
    "answer": "meetyou, know",
    "answerDetails": "So nice to meetyou."
  },
  {
    "id": 3493,
    "question": "sabrá",
    "questionDetails": "Sabrá hablar español después de estudiar en el extranjero.",
    "answer": "she will know",
    "answerDetails": "She will know how to speak Spanish after studying abroad."
  },
  {
    "id": 3494,
    "question": "canal",
    "questionDetails": "El Canal de la Mancha.",
    "answer": "channel",
    "answerDetails": "The (English) Channel."
  },
  {
    "id": 3495,
    "question": "conociendo",
    "questionDetails": "Conociendo a los nuestros.",
    "answer": "knowing, getting acquainted",
    "answerDetails": "Just knowing on our own."
  },
  {
    "id": 3496,
    "question": "barbaridad",
    "answer": "atrocity"
  },
  {
    "id": 3497,
    "question": "casados",
    "questionDetails": "Ambos casados con diferentes personas.",
    "answer": "married, weds",
    "answerDetails": "Both of them married to different people."
  },
  {
    "id": 3498,
    "question": "métete",
    "questionDetails": "Solo métete lo por la garganta.",
    "answer": "shove, get, tuck",
    "answerDetails": "Just shove it down your throat."
  },
  {
    "id": 3499,
    "question": "ventaja",
    "questionDetails": "Sus coches tienen la ventaja sobre sus rivales ‘.",
    "answer": "edge, bonus, perk",
    "answerDetails": "His cars have the edge over his rivals’."
  },
  {
    "id": 3500,
    "question": "tráeme",
    "answer": "Bring"
  }
]
